Oh, yeah.
There it is.
Guys, I'm in such a great mood.
It's Friday and I can't stop thinking about this game.
I want to play it all the time.
I think I may be addicted.
It's a hard game to put down.
It's a hard game to stop thinking about.
I want to find more perks.
I want to find more spells.
I want to do all the things.
Also, I have a bunch of stuff in my notepad here, by the way.
Stuff I want to do in Noita that I've been thinking about.
Now I finally put them all down and organized in my notes.
So this includes exploring that hut near the ocean some more, go to the ancient laboratory.
There's all the cloud stuff.
And then we have that demon eye that produces platforms in the west.
I want to try to go all the way up there and kill whatever I find.
I want to do, and that's just a small subset of the things I have written down here, but I have plans.
That's what I'm trying to say here.
You're not addicted.
You can stop at any moment you want to.
Honest.
Definitely.
Yes.
How have you been enjoying Prey so far?
Bro.
In case you couldn't tell from the videos yet, but I love that game.
It's great.
What a fantastic atmosphere of that game.
Love it.
You should seek professional health.
No, but I don't want to.
I want to stay addicted.
What can I say?
Sorbitus!
What's up, man?
Thank you.
And Will Big... Will Big Dog.
W.L.
Big Dog.
Welcome to the community.
Thanks for subscribing, man.
And Fleeksoik.
Isn't that Fleeksoik?
I'll take it, though.
Fleeksoik, also you, thank you very much.
So excited to watch me play more.
Nice.
Very nice.
Would you check the game options before starting?
Sure.
What should I check?
Noiser eviction is a great joy, definitely.
I have fallen prey to it.
Not those options?
Wait, which options?
Wait, what are we talking about?
I'm so confused.
I'm going to rate this stream 5 out of 5 stars on Letterboxd.
I don't know what that means.
It's taking note of game modes.
Wait, what?
Input options?
Guys, I have no idea what you guys are saying.
I'm so confused.
Turn the freaky croissant mode on?
Okay, you guys are fucking with me.
Oh, when I start a new run!
Oh, I already know about these.
I have looked at them in the past.
I know there's a thing called a daily run.
I commented on it.
Nightmare for a more challenging experience?
How about no?
For right now, at least.
I feel like this game is hard enough as it is.
Daily practice run?
Oh, I see.
From a randomized spot?
Interesting.
Okay.
Oh, we can do a daily run sometime, for sure.
Definitely.
I mean, I can do that now.
It's pretty much the same game, right?
It's just going to be a seed that everyone else also has access to?
Or is there a difference?
I could do it now, I guess.
Yeah, I don't want it if it spoils anything.
They have all the spells unlocked?
Okay, in that case, I'm just going to do my thing.
Okay, gotcha.
I'm just going to play a new game as always.
I wonder if I can see my deaths.
I think I'm at like 40-something deaths.
I died a lot.
Nothing compared to Rainworld, though.
Holy shit!
Like, I gotta say Rainworld so far?
Way harder.
That game is brutal, dude.
But we'll have to see.
I feel like this game right here is as hard as you want it to be, you know?
If that makes sense.
You can sort of create your own difficulty with the ones you make.
And the choices you make in the game.
Oh yeah, I can't see my deaths in the game.
I have to look at it while I'm in the game, right?
Okay, I'm just going to start, man.
I have things to do.
Alright, you guys are shut down.
No offense.
I'm going to play my game here.
Everything is foggy!
For some reason.
What the hell is going on?
Look at this!
Wait a minute, is that normal?
Why is everything so foggy?
What the hell?
Hmm.
Well, dude, I am just fucking excited to have a new run, you know?
And find new perks.
Try new combinations.
I mean, but if I... Whoa!
But if I find a combination...
That's a great start.
The air is filled with fungal spores.
Is that why it's foggy?
What the hell does that mean?
Why is it filled with fungal spores?
I don't like that.
That makes me unhappy.
In fact, I have become bothered by that.
Die, horta!
Why is everything shaking already?
What the hell is going on?
What's that?
Oh, wait a minute!
It's a broken wand!
I know exactly what to do with that!
Remember?
Uh, I actually do have bombs, so I could get through here.
But there's a bunch of oil, so that's a bit dangerous.
Let me go around.
Uh, actually, wait with that.
We're exploring the top first.
Stick to the core principles here.
Core principles.
Wait, why is everything...
Why is there so much oil?
Look at all this oil!
There's oil everywhere.
Get rid of that.
Eh, there we go.
Look at all that oil.
Wait, that guy, horta, right there.
He needs to die.
There we go.
Good thing you can take care of coal with this wand.
That's a start.
Release the oil!
That way I can also be released.
Almost.
There we go.
Dude, everything is oil.
Always has been.
I just thought of that astronaut meme.
Always makes me laugh.
Okay.
Blood me up instead, huh?
How about that?
Okay.
What is that up there?
Oh, it's a fungus.
Oh, is that the fungal spore situation thing?
You know what?
I need to get through here.
Yep.
That's fine.
I should wait for that fire to go away.
Or should I?
Nah.
I can grab it.
Ah, shit.
Also, wait a minute.
What am I filled with?
Oh, no, this is not water.
See, this is already a mistake.
I already fucked up.
There's water here.
Oh, my God.
I need to get rid of this and get some water.
Throw that in there, even though it pains me.
Oh, you know what?
I can just drink it all, actually, instead.
That's way better.
That way I can also crit.
Hey.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
This is good.
Also, I'm actually drinking right now.
You can still fit more in my stomach.
I also kind of want to try and understand this system here.
See, what is the upside to filling my stomach?
I see only downsides.
I don't understand.
Get through there.
Whoa!
Wait, wasn't that a much bigger explosion than usual?
Am I crazy?
I got the broken wand.
I know exactly what to do with that.
We can repair it, baby.
I figured that out last time.
That's actually one of the mysteries I've been thinking about forever.
The broken wand, you know?
Finally got an answer to that one.
There's still many mysteries left, though.
Like all those eggs you can find?
The electrical eggs?
The fire eggs?
There's got to be something with those.
You got to put them somewhere, you know?
Man, is it just me or is this...
Is this hemisphere right here way harder to traverse than normal?
Just like everything is closed off.
I'm scared.
I'm not scared.
I was kidding.
I don't really get scared in video games, you know?
That's a fact.
I'm immune to that sort of thing.
Jumpscares?
Mm-mm.
Never had one of those.
What do we got here?
Concentrated mana.
I feel like I should start using potions more.
You know, like berserkium and that sort of stuff.
Hemis?
Can I not get in here?
God damn it.
Is he a horta?
Okay, so I will not get in there.
That's fine with me.
I have one bomb left.
I could do something with that.
Health!
Oh no, I can't get it.
Okay, you know what?
If there's health, we got to take it.
There's just no... no argument there.
Got it.
Okay, 74 HP.
So here's what I actually realized last time.
Kind of an important point.
At the end of Last Dream, I sort of speculated that if I don't lose any HP in the first level, and maybe the second even, that is gonna be so fucking extremely important later on.
Because you only have a set amount of heals, right?
Oops.
And if you can choose to heal either like 100 HP in the first levels, or not take damage in the first levels, and then heal like thousands of HP later with that same healing buff.
Right?
Oh my god, look at that.
They are protecting that chest.
And I can't get in.
I have no more bombs.
I gotta find ones.
There's so many goodies in this level here.
Holy shit.
I do wonder what the whole fungal spores in the air means.
What's that?
Oh, fungus.
Yeah.
Everything is fungalized.
That's a dead end.
This is one of the hardest hemispheres ever, when it comes to traversal.
I feel like my every path is blocked.
And there's so much oil!
Never had that much oil.
Up here?
Look at that.
They explode.
But only when you hit them, I think.
We have here collapsed mines.
Man, it's crazy how I haven't found a single wand yet.
Why does that always happen when you say it out loud?
You know, it's like an anti jinx.
Damn, sick crit.
What do we got?
Arrows!
That's not bad.
Except I kind of want something to explode things with.
We do actually have something here, but I can't sort of take it with me.
I can only kick it.
I want telekinetic pickup.
Such a cool perk.
One of my favorite, I have to say.
It's just too much fun.
Uh-oh.
Somehow that coal didn't catch on fire.
That is exactly what?
Acceleration.
No thanks.
Not right now.
Also, how much does this do?
Three damage, and this does five.
Right.
And this one goes through enemies, I think, because of the slice.
A frog.
Jesus!
That dude had the sickest plan ever.
Wow.
That was insane.
I got owned.
Completely outplayed.
Uh-oh.
What's that?
Oh, it's some kind of bullshit liquid that is on fire.
Oh!
Oh god, this is bad.
You want this?
Get rid of it.
Oh god, this is a disaster.
36 HP.
This is already not looking great.
But you know what?
I'm not gonna let that get me down.
This is the run.
I'm telling you.
Oh, that guy had a bad day.
I'm sorry, froggy.
Oh, another frog.
That just scared the crap out of me.
Hello!
Oh my god, I got hit by that.
Terrible!
I'm actually dying.
Dying!
This is horrible.
This hemisphere is nuts, I'm telling you.
It's cursed.
What's up here?
Oh, that's...
Oh, that's the root of the tree right there.
Can I?
I refuse to go through the portal yet.
I simply refuse.
I say no to that.
God damn it, go down the patch.
Unfortunately, this is not gonna...
That works.
Come on, sir.
Nice!
That was a sick shot, threading the needle.
Hey, guys.
Wow, you have a lot of HP.
Why are these frogs so tanky?
That's what I wonder.
So is there a way for me to get up there and grab that wand?
I don't think so.
Man, what is in here?
I am... You know what?
I'm gonna write that down, damn it.
I need to figure out what's in there.
Let's say...
Dark area.
West.
And hemisphere.
Explore that shit.
That's what I'm gonna write here.
With a light.
I don't like the moaning in the background that I'm hearing.
It makes me uncomfortable.
Okay.
Good.
We gotta find the light source and get in there.
That's on the objectives.
That guy is still not dead, huh?
Come on, man.
Where'd he go?
Hey!
Uh-oh.
Haha, back.
Return to sender.
Nice.
The portal is there.
I have an out if I want it.
Holy shit!
Never mind!
I have no idea where that came from.
Let's save the dead.
I need to see that.
Oh my god, he was standing right here.
Unbelievable.
Wow.
Okay.
Well, you know, first death doesn't count.
We all know that.
It was kind of a crap start anyway.
That's what I say.
I have a snow potion.
Two spark bolts.
And some TNT.
And it's dark outside!
I don't know what...
Is that significant?
I wonder if there are certain...
things in the world that change depending on the time of day.
And environmental effects, you know?
Like rain or something.
I'm gonna go up here, of course, and grab the HP.
Oh, dude, dude, dude, dude, dude.
Let's try something.
Oh no, actually, I'm gonna do that later.
Because remember the hut?
We saw an image of a tablet on the wall.
Kind of want to bring a tablet over there, but I should probably go there when I...
Oh my god, I can't get up there.
I can totally do this.
Come on.
How is that possible?
Say what?
Okay, fine.
I'll use another one.
Okay.
There.
Very nice.
Kick that stone.
Always gotta kick that stone.
Oh, the snow is especially high today.
Whoops.
One more.
Beautiful.
Yoink.
I will take this with me as well, actually.
Hello.
Aww.
Oh, no.
No, you know what?
No, I'm not gonna dig for that.
Nope.
I'm gonna grab that later.
Can't believe it just got buried in the snow.
Yes, I know, the great entity is angry.
I do wonder what that entity is.
And where I can find it.
Needs a good ass kicking, I reckon.
Let's see if that hits something this time.
Doi!
It totally did.
This air is still filled with fungal spores.
What does that mean?
Why is that a thing?
What is that?
Just the fungus?
It was moving, though.
That guy is somehow protected by an invisible force field.
Come here.
What the hell am I hitting?
What?
I'm hitting some kind of terrain, I think.
Cut!
Okay, snow is useless.
Noted.
Can I drink snow?
You're feeling cold inside.
Movement is difficult.
Ingesting snow?
Right, brain freeze.
Okay.
Is it me or has the game gotten harder?
I feel like suddenly the hemisphere is significantly more difficult than it used to be.
Maybe it does that when you reach a certain number of games played.
Or maybe I got worse.
It's possible.
I'm not going to deny that possibility.
No, okay.
So quiet in here now.
I have a bunch of TNT, that's nice.
That means I can go places.
Why is it so quiet?
Emmys!
That guy can stand there.
I don't care.
That's a weirdly empty room.
Thank God there's no oil this time.
It was filled with it just before.
I'm going to make my way down.
Yep.
Garahurta?
What else?
I feel like difficulty must be linked to the whole the air is filled with fungal...
Fungal spores.
What is that?
Can I actually eat that?
Tripping some!
Yo!
Look at my screen!
You feel in harmony with the magical forces.
Cost ingesting weird?
Fuck it!
That's fucking awesome, dude.
Look at my screen, dude.
Hold on, I'm going to eat some more.
Let's get hella high.
We got to get high in the hemisphere, man.
There we go.
That's awesome.
That's so cool that they added this little thing, you know?
Oh, there's a chest!
I see a chest!
Uh-oh, I'm stuck.
I'm actually stuck!
This is a bad trip!
How do I get out?
I'm actually stuck.
Oh, there we go, there we go.
That was scary.
I thought I just bricked my game.
Invisibly...
Everything is warbled as fuck, dude.
Look at the water.
It's all messed up.
Actually kind of a cool effect.
This guy wants some TNT, I can tell.
That was a perfect hit.
Even the sounds are warbled.
Uh-oh.
Oh, I got hit!
Oh my god.
I'm playing terribly, but I'm also high as fuck, so...
That's my excuse.
Water, water, water, water, water.
That's not water, that's ice!
Get out of the water.
Jesus!
Oh, it's like a weird effect on the audio here.
Yo, I'm tripping a lot.
Oh, 78 seconds.
Tripping some.
Okay.
I wonder if you can die from it if you trip too hard.
Uh-oh.
I see you there, sir.
You know what?
I'll leave you there.
I don't want to deal with you at all.
I wonder if there's some kind of gameplay effect being high.
Maybe I'd do more damage.
Or the enemy does... something different.
Hey, come here.
Yo, Hemis!
Thank you for that gold.
What's that?
Invisibilium, right.
Apparently that broke.
Gotcha.
I am invisible.
I am coming for that chest.
That's also invisibilium.
I can get in there.
It's easy as pie.
Is pie easy?
What's that?
Oh, was there just money in that chest?
Copper pouch.
Thank you.
Okay, I'm almost not tripping anymore.
Oh, interesting.
It says tripping, but before it said tripping some.
Like, just a little bit.
I kind of want to get really high and see what it says.
Oh, man.
Porta!
With weird frog clothing.
Come here.
Oh my god, he has a lot of HP suddenly.
Also, he dropped no gold, I don't think.
Hey.
Frogster.
Jesus!
He did a lot of damage.
Little piece of shit.
Fucking frogs, man.
Oh, you know what?
Watch this.
No.
No, wrong way.
Come on.
Ah, whatever.
This is why I want telekinetic lift pickup.
I'll throw a manipulator, whatever it's called.
Telekinesis, I think it's just called, actually.
Gotcha.
You know what's really weird?
So watch, this one does three damage.
Right?
Watch this.
I'm going to shoot someone.
Didn't it just do six damage?
Am I crazy?
Or is it because I go cuck, cuck, cuck, and then it adds it?
I think that's what's happening, but...
Ah, a path of fire blocks my way.
I'll leave it burning for a while.
I'm going to grab that later, I guess.
It's not in the stars for me at this moment.
Do you want to get up there?
Beautiful hit.
Oh, shit.
It's fine.
It's totally fine.
There it is.
Let's see if the burning stopped.
What the fuck is going on there?
Why is it burning so much?
I can't even go this way, because it's also burning here.
Somehow this coal is not burning.
Isn't that weird?
Okay, it is burning, but very slowly.
I wonder if that's because of the fungal air.
Does that affect this somehow?
Might call me crazy, but that usually burns quicker, no?
Man, that guy has HP.
Did I get him?
I got him.
Oh, yeah, he bleeds lava.
Let's be careful there.
Yeah, that's not good.
That's actually really bad.
Rip money?
Okay, I can do it now.
I can do it now.
Yes!
Ooh, energy sphere!
That's one of my favorites.
Fuck yeah.
Oh!
Fucking frogs do like ten damage.
Gotta be careful of that.
I've been here.
I'm gonna use the remaining TNT here.
If I need to.
Okay, there's another portal.
That's great.
Another potential exit.
Let's get rid of that.
Boink!
Wait, that's not my energy sphere.
I can't hit!
I'm unable to hit.
Unst- Ooh!
I love that one.
I love unstable teleportation.
Gotcha!
This fucker killed me last run, or almost did.
Shot a- Ooh, look at the air here.
Very fungal-y.
Uh, swamp.
That's that?
Egg?
What?
It's just an egg!
It's not a fire egg or a frost egg, it's just an egg.
Duh!
He's my friend!
Let's go hunting together.
He's my hunting dog.
This guy's gonna get a TNT in his face.
Watch.
Boink!
Hehehe!
Oh yeah!
Oh, and there's a wand!
Wait, there's two hortas now!
What?
Are they multiplying?
What's happening?
A black hole!
Fuck yeah!
That's a digging, right there.
Three charges, not bad.
Chests!
Chest, chest, chest.
Got him.
Gimme that gold.
I bet he good.
Ho!
Barney!
Hand over the money.
Now the horta- why am I a horta's not following me?
Somehow that guy's not aggressive at all.
Oh shit!
We're fine.
That was almost a disaster.
Wait, why is he so passive?
Mino comprende.
Oops, that's fire.
I'm standing next to a- coal!
Oh shit, that just broke that, huh?
Got him!
He has lava though, so be careful.
38 HP, I already messed that up, man.
I'm really trying my hardest to get through the- ooh, another chest.
Get through the first level without losing any HP.
It's not working out well.
Ah shit, that's all gonna burn now, isn't it?
I'm gonna need a third one!
I have- wait, what?
Oh, I don't have enough mana.
Come on.
Yes, yes, yes.
That thing's gonna burn now?
Oh, hello.
Nice!
Fuck yeah, man!
It's like one of the best things you can find in a chest.
As far as I know.
Uh, it's gonna be kind of a pain to get there though.
Can I take out the fire with copper?
Let's try.
Yo, that actually works really well!
What the hell?
Dude!
I just discovered that- that's awesome.
Bunch of polymorphine.
Hmm...
So to get that polymorphine, I have to let myself get polymorphed.
I mean, it's not the end of the world, so why not?
Boink!
Oh wait, I couldn't pick it up in time?
Oh shit, I see the issue.
Hold on.
Uh, maybe if I...
Oh wait, this one can't even shoot it!
It's not enough mana!
That sucks.
I was about to make a hole here.
But I can still do that, actually.
There we go.
Drain that crap.
I don't want polymorphine, man.
If anything, I want unstable polymorphine.
Now that's the shit.
That's my jam.
Circle of stillness.
Um...
Do I want that?
It's a kind of a sick wand, honestly.
Isn't it?
Like, look at the stats of it.
It's basically superior in every way to this, if you just use the same spell.
I know it's shuffle, but...
Um...
Let's...
Hmm...
Question is, though.
Do I want to keep the energy spheres, or do I want to keep the spark bolts?
Maybe I actually want to keep the spark bolts.
That's fine with me.
I can dig it, you know?
Well, I can't dig, but I wish I could.
There's a dude.
Hey, dude.
Yeah.
Hoi!
Yeah, you bastard.
Got him.
Okay, let's not grab that money.
Yeah, get out of here.
Plate safe.
No unnecessary risks here.
No, sir.
What do we have here?
Oh, that's the...
That's the dangerous guy right there.
One of the hardest enemies in the hemisphere.
Uh-oh.
Don't bleed that crap, will ya?
Question is, is there any point to killing this guy?
I'm going to try and pay attention if anything changes when I kill him.
Okay, that's going to burn through that.
That's awesome.
In fact, what is this again?
A circle of stillness?
Feel a freezing...
Maybe I'll try and kill him with that.
Hey, come here.
Yeah, you see me.
You mad now!
Right.
Boink!
Wait, this is the Chaos Bolt, right?
That does something mysterious when it hits someone.
Gives them bad luck or something.
Yeah!
I mean, it's actually kind of a nice spot I'm in here.
Oh yeah, this is great.
Damn, lots of HP.
Hand over the money!
Many thanks.
Oh!
Very interesting hemisphere.
What is... Oh, that's the polymorphine.
Before we go down there, I want to go up first.
Ah, dead end!
Crap!
And I can't get through here either.
Oh!
Oh, don't walk in that, dummy!
There's got to be a way here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, this looks good.
Yep.
And then we're here now.
Awesome.
Let's kill some hortas.
Kind of look like dogs, right?
Small dogs.
Dog people.
I'm in a dog mensch.
A real dog mensch.
That's funny.
Okay, I got a pile of gunpowder.
Thank you.
Hmm...
No.
I will not use my dynamite.
I really wanted to, but I'm not gonna.
Oh.
It's Barney.
I've won!
Now we're talking, baby!
Is that toxic rock?
Oh, shit, that's bad.
Why is that here?
I'm telling you, this hemisphere is not what it used to be, man.
Things of...
Ooh.
That's toxic sludge.
But you know what?
We don't have water, so...
Will this actually do something?
Oh!
Toxic ice.
That makes sense.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
So I guess I can't make it untoxic.
Wait, is toxic ice bad to stand on?
Oh, it's bad to stand on.
Yeah, okay.
Hmm.
We need water.
Any water?
In fact, I don't...
Wait, snow.
Maybe snow will work.
Snow is water.
Not there.
Here.
Yes!
Mix it.
Look at that!
Fixed.
Now just...
Yeah, break that...
Oh, that's awesome.
Look at that.
I break the toxic ice.
That's cool.
I mean, literally.
Whoa.
A circle of thunder.
What is it with these circles I'm getting here?
So many circles.
Uh...
Do I want that, though?
A field of electrifying magic?
Hmm.
The wand itself...
does not really seem that great.
Wait a minute.
Yeah, it doesn't seem that great.
Does it?
I don't want it.
I will not take it.
I'm gonna go this way.
Hmm.
Kind of want that spell that lets me see things.
All seeing eye.
Another wand.
Oh, no, it's locked in.
No problem, though.
We have two more TNTs.
Perfect hit.
That's what I'm talking about.
A magic missile.
Now, that's pretty good.
I do like that.
Should I take that?
0.10, 0.07.
I like the stats on this wand more, though.
I could replace it with this.
You know, this is actually kind of a shit wand anyway.
And TNT is about to run out anyway.
Let's do it, man.
Fuck it.
Fuck the TNT.
This will do just as good a job.
And there's health.
Talking sludge.
We put snow in there.
Then we mix it.
Beautiful.
I love that this is like a thing.
That that works, you know.
That guy right there, I want to kill with the magic missile.
Or actually.
Hey, you know, what if I have an idea?
Hey.
But it worked.
It worked.
I broke his ass.
He was frozen.
Well, I learned my lesson there.
He explodes in a big cloud of gas.
Or acid, I should say.
But you know what?
Proof of concept.
It works.
You can totally kick enemies that are frozen.
I don't know if it did more than normal damage, but...
You know, that's what I usually imagine.
Unstable crystal, hmm.
Don't want to bother with that going up.
Man, I've died a lot today already.
This is crazy.
Okay.
Now we're going to play patient, okay?
This was just a warm up.
I'm going to take a sip now.
And then all collectively, all of us in unison, we will realize that today is Friday.
And we shall be happy.
And thus, the community was happy.
Another broken wand.
Now I cannot die.
I need to bring this to the repair place.
I'm on a mission.
The slowest mission in existence.
I shall not do anything foolish this time.
But you know what?
An expert is a person who's made a lot of mistakes.
More than the average person, right?
You can't get to that level unless you make those mistakes.
Portas everywhere.
This is...
It makes me un...
I don't like it.
They jump around a lot.
There we go.
And there's a wand immediately.
Great start.
With a magic missile, baby.
Yes, sir.
Come to me.
Come here.
Didn't even see you there.
Interestingly, if they're close to the roof of a ground, the thing will actually pop up upstairs.
I've noticed that multiple times now.
Oh, shit!
Hey, miss.
Acceleration.
Yes, please.
I'll take it.
We've got a hoodlum.
It kind of looks like a hoodlum to me.
Like a troublemaker.
You fucker!
Oh, he died.
Oh, nice, nice, nice, nice.
Somehow I thought he survived that.
Another horta?
So far, perfect play, by the way.
We have been warmed up.
It's impossible for me to use that excuse now.
We are warmed up.
So this is peak performance, what you're seeing right now.
And it will stay peak.
Just watch.
Boink!
Haha!
You see that?
That's peak.
That's totally peak.
Put out the fire.
Man, I see.
Don't go in the fire.
That's it.
Kind of want fire immunity again.
That was the tits when I had it.
Really nice.
But it came at a cost, right?
Because we were bleeding oil, so...
We were all slippery and shit all the time.
Not actually that great, but...
I think it was totally worth it.
But the fire immunity?
God damn.
That's a hort!
Whoa.
We're in pheromone.
Why is that just there?
It sort of appeared up here.
Suddenly, did you notice?
I'm going to go around and go in like that.
Because that thing is burning away.
But that means the fire dude is going to be released.
And that's something we don't like.
But it's okay.
We're going to have to deal with it.
In fact, I can't get around, it seems.
Maybe I'll have to resort to harsher measures here.
Also, do I have mud?
I was about to say I need water.
Is that enough to make water?
It is.
At least, swamp.
I can make swamp with it.
Boink!
Blow it!
Yeah, that works.
I was too close to that one.
Nice.
Pretty good.
I'm happy.
Make swamp.
Actually, swamp is good.
That can totally douse fire.
Right, so he's released now.
As expected.
Just try and gently go around that fire.
Do that because it's fun.
Let me try and make our way to the fire, dude.
Another want!
The fuck?
Piece of enemy just fell down.
Look at me playing so carefully.
I'm converting every surface.
That's the new me, you know?
Safety comes first.
Oh, another...
Whoa, he has a want.
Hello?
Hey, come here, come here, come here.
Come here.
I'm totally gone on magic messing with his ass.
Let's drop off.
You fucker, that was my strategy.
Gotcha!
Oh, look at him bleeding lava.
Sure sign of my victory.
Huerta?
I wonder if Huerta means dog in Finnish, actually.
Because it's kind of close to the Danish hud... for dog.
And I'm actually not sure how close Danish is to Finnish.
I don't think it is close at all.
Because when you look at Finnish words, you start to question your sanity.
No offense.
There it is!
But this is danger.
But we have mud.
Mud it up, baby!
Hup!
What's that?
Wait, what?
Oh, I thought the liquid set extra max HP.
I'm so confused.
Awesome!
Very nice.
Mission completed there.
Now we go back over here.
Wait, where was it?
Oh, hello.
Man, I'm standing on a bunch of coal.
And...gud powder!
This is bad.
And there's a lamp!
Gaah!
Okay.
Phew!
Got him.
What if I kick this?
What if I eat it?
Oh, I think I already tried that once, actually.
Didn't work.
The whole thing was about to collapse down on me.
Actually, I think it still might.
Oh, shit.
I gotta get out of here.
We don't want to be there when that thing collapses.
It's not worth it.
What's that?
Oh, look at that!
Another broken one!
Dude, we gotta make it to that part now.
I think it was an easy base.
Yo!
Look at that!
That's so sneaky!
I see you.
That was actually a bit risky what I just did there.
Wait!
Wait, there's a wand right here.
Oh, it's from the guy I killed.
Do I want this wand?
Hold on.
.03, .23.
190...
Yeah!
Yeah, I want this wand!
Yo, that's a sick wand!
What the fuck?
That's a great wand.
Okay, let's get to that chest.
Cheers, everybody.
That thing's gonna burn.
Let's see what's in it.
Let me help it along.
See, I shouldn't have done that yet.
Oh, wait.
That's not gold.
That's the Kivaskivi.
That is the fire rock or fire egg.
Oh, Jesus.
Everything's collapsing here.
Do I want the Kivaskivi?
I think I do, because I want to do experiments.
Acceleration...
Let's actually get rid of it.
Just put it here.
And to take that, we've got a porcelain mud.
Oh, it's actually down here now.
That's actually kind of a safe way to...
Oh, wait.
I have no more mud.
Shit.
Let's grab some water.
Oh, that was not a lot of water I just got.
Shit.
Wait, I see a bunch of water.
Oh, there's a lot of water here.
Oh, we good, boy.
Oh, yeah.
Fill me up.
That's it.
There we go.
Look at that.
Man, this is just producing steam.
Why is it not putting out the fire?
Got it.
This tiny rock looks most fiery, but when touched, only a pleasant warmth can be felt.
You know what?
I'm going to be on the lookout for symbols in the game world depicting this.
Because remember at the cabin?
The little hut we saw near the ocean.
There was an image of a tablet.
And I think I need to do something there with a tablet.
But I'm going to do that later.
But I want to look for similar things, you know?
Also, that tablet, you can put it on the pedestal at the very top, right?
And then we have the broken wand that can also be put on something and something happens.
So it's all about putting things on other things.
What's that?
Ambrosia potion.
Hmm.
Fuck me.
Why do I do this all the time?
God damn it.
I hate myself.
I was going to throw it away and grab the potion.
Wait, we have a potion here, though.
I will take that instead.
Ah!
Enemy!
Hello, sir.
Would you like some of this?
Holy shit.
Man, the magic missile is really effective against certain enemies.
Like they...
I guess it's because he's made of flammable material.
Is that the reason?
I think that's the reason.
Makes a lot of sense to me.
God damn.
Where'd the potion go?
It broke somehow.
What the hell?
Shit, I got hit.
Oh, no.
Follow me up.
This is a disaster.
Everything is falling apart.
Get him!
Barney's here?
Come here.
Alright, fine.
Let's kill this Huerta.
Look!
You see that?
The gold nugget spawned up here.
When there's not enough room physically in the world for it to spawn, it spawns upstairs.
Aha!
Here we go.
In fact, I'm going to drink all of this.
And we're going to grab that Ambrosia.
Whoa, I'm so fast, boy.
Ah!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Jesus.
That is really fast.
Fill me up.
I can't believe if that actually is from all.
That's fucking crazy.
How is this not broken as fuck?
You know?
Gimme.
Yeah.
Let me try here.
Hey!
It doesn't work!
Fucking liar!
What the hell?
Unless I didn't have the buff on, somehow.
But it didn't say like 90%.
God damn.
More acceleration.
I don't want that.
What is in here?
All right.
Man, the frogs do a lot of damage.
And they're small and hard to hit, you know?
Kind of annoying.
Crit, baby!
Got a shoddy man.
What's up, shoddy?
Oh, his gun is cocked.
That scares me.
There we go.
Taking care of.
You can call me the cleanser.
It's what I do.
The issue now is, though, I don't have any water potion.
And I almost want to say water is more important.
Because of fire.
Fire is bad.
Fire is probably one of the main ways that I take damage in this game.
You know, just accidentally putting myself on fire a little bit.
Taking a little bit of damage here and there.
But it adds up in the end.
That was a nice crit.
What's that?
Levitation?
I'm getting all kinds of shit out.
Don't you fucking throw that at me.
There we go.
Also, if I drink this, it makes me sick.
I have to bathe in it.
That is like the thing.
Boink!
Doing!
Vomit!
Can I drink the vomit?
Oh, you totally can!
That's nasty, bruh.
Why am I able to drink the vomit?
With the blood stain I just left.
Man...
Magic missile time, maybe?
Yeah, that worked.
Also, I'm bloody now, so I crit.
Damn!
Ah,
had to sneeze there.
Don't throw!
The guy picked up the wand!
That could have been really bad.
It's a bomb wand.
Um...
.07...
One...
Hmm.
Maybe?
Maybe I do want that.
I don't want the unstable crystallized caesium.
I don't like unstable crystallized caesium.
It brings me unhappiness.
And I'm the sort of person that just aims for that happiness.
So...
Don't want it.
Look at this now!
Shit!
That's fine, it makes a huge explosion.
What was in there?
Kami!
What the hell is that?
Looks like a small rat skull or something.
Okay, steel's not gonna burn obviously, so come on.
I mean...
You know...
You can't melt steel beams.
I honestly forgot that sentence or the meme.
Oh, it's a...
I need to make space.
Let me get rid of that.
Well, that starts a fire.
What?!
Can't be thrown to summon a cozy hut?!
Does that mean?
What the hell?
Yo!
I need to...
Try that.
But I feel like not here.
What could that mean?
A cozy hut?
I wonder if that's like a resting place.
Do I get to heal or something?
That would be insane.
What the hell?
Kami.
There you go, frog.
These are the roots of the tree.
It is the queen of the surgh!
A good ol' in-control reference there.
R.I.P.
Man, I love that guy's humor.
Too bad he isn't around anymore.
Boink!
Man, I kind of want to dig from below.
And get up there, you know what I mean?
Uh, sir?
Please don't kill me!
God damn, man.
He led me into a corner.
I guess I pushed myself into a corner.
But you know what I mean.
There we go.
Give me that gold.
Also, 418 gold so far?
That's not bad.
This is actually a great start.
I like this start.
I'm pleased.
And then we have moaning in the back.
Love to hear it.
Actually, I hate it, but you know.
Someone is doing the moaning here in the hemisphere.
Uh, okay.
Holy shit!
You scared me, brother!
Hand it over.
Are we about done with this area?
Methinks?
We may be.
Let's be careful here.
There could be a guy.
Actually, I hear more stuff.
I'm gonna keep looking.
Think about it like this.
The first re-roll costs 200.
So I would like at least 600 to do a second one if I need to.
Nice!
Good thing I just found that.
Uh, what the hell happened here?
A bunch of acid, I guess.
What is that?
What the hell is that?
Slimy egg.
No, no thanks.
Oh, it's that dude down there.
We're gonna magic missile him.
I hit him.
I did not hit him.
Because he has a bunch of shit in front of him.
Let me go this way.
Hello!
There's a party down there, man.
Ah, shit, that ain't water.
Oh, but that works, I guess, because protection.
I mean, that's nice.
Throw it on after the fact, it clears your status.
That's actually great to know.
Pretty neat.
What do we got here?
Levitation.
I don't think I want that.
Man, I was swimming in gold last run, or not last, but the last big run.
And now it's like, completely different.
There we go.
It's a big hemisphere.
Or maybe it's always the same size, I'm not actually sure.
Sometimes it feels bigger because you have access to more stuff, you know?
Other times, all the areas are locked off.
And you don't have any digging capability.
But I do, in fact, have digging capabilities.
A bit more, at least.
I can't hit shit.
Oh my god!
What?!
Just like that, right here?
That's fucking awesome.
Uh, I'm glad I didn't leave.
Glowing lands, obviously.
Let me take that.
And let me do... what's that one?
I don't want sparkly bounce.
I will take this one as well.
Fuck yeah, dude.
No reason not to.
Now I'm going to collect some more money.
That was great, man.
Very cool.
Let me...
Am I la- I'm not lazy.
I'm not lazy.
I'm patient and I'm precise.
This way.
Do not want to make holes.
Just want to plug them.
Now that is a lot of oil.
I bet you there's something down there.
Burn it all.
That is glorious.
Fuck yeah.
Let's see.
Is there anything down there?
Come on!
There's got to be something!
Maybe not.
Goddamn, okay.
That's a bummer.
Okay, but now we can't leave because we need at least 600 gold and we need to find it somehow.
Let's explore the right side a bit more.
Right.
I was here.
But then I left and went left instead for some reason.
And I don't remember why.
Okay, nothing there.
Secret there!
Sup,
dude?
Fungus.
We could go on a trip if we wanted to.
Kind of want to try to eat it all.
Should I?
Ooh, let's try.
Wait, what's that?
Oh, I thought this was a huge treasure chest.
Oh!
Dude, just stand there.
I'm not doing anything.
Just standing and it does something.
No, wait.
No, no, no.
I accidentally ate, I think.
Yeah, eat it all, dude.
Eat it all.
Fuck yeah.
Eat it all, dude.
Tripping balls!
I love it.
And there's a chest!
What?
You feel something has changed?
You hear?
I didn't see that!
I didn't see what it says!
Wait a minute, there was a thing?
F11?
No, I can't see the text!
Damn it!
Okay, whatever.
Holy no!
Fuck off, man!
I didn't see that, dude.
God damn it.
That was so sad.
That's what happens when you trip balls.
And you play with explosions.
Don't mix the two, it's a bad idea.
Well, that happened.
And now I have a blood potion.
Which is fine with me, because if I drink that, nothing happens, except I get minimally satiated.
I was kind of hoping I would get crit.
But I have to stand in it, I think, so...
It's interesting that some liquids you can drink, and it will give you some kind of effect, like a potion.
Like you would expect.
But then there's other liquids that when you drink, it just makes you sick.
Such as, I guess, oil.
If you drink that, that's bad.
Which kind of makes sense.
I'm not sure what I'm trying to say with all this.
The game makes sense.
I don't know what I'm expecting, you know?
Oh, drink varmint?
What does that do?
Oh, it makes you sick.
Makes sense.
Okay, so I have three normal bombs.
And there's a wand.
Heck yeah.
There's two wands right next to each other!
What the fuck?
Should I just blow my way in?
Fuck yeah.
Run!
Just get the safe distance, always.
We very patiently wait for this fire to go out.
There's a small wand, and there's a big wand.
Which wand do you think will be better?
The right one, or the left one?
Let's see, I'm gonna say...
I'm actually gonna say the right one.
I think size doesn't matter in this case.
I'm gonna kill these guys first.
There we go.
Man, there's so many people here!
All the hemises!
I guess we are in the hemisphere, so...
It doesn't make sense.
This is their natural habitat.
Let's see.
Bouncing burst?
That's actually... not bad.
And rain cloud.
And it's shuffled.
You know what?
I was right.
The right one was better.
And look at that, mana charge speed 10.
Yikes.
But the good part is...
that rain cloud is actually not the worst thing.
You know, you can make a lot of water with that.
In fact, I may do it now, because we need water.
Let's do it right here.
Fill it up!
And then we empty the blood, because we don't want blood.
Blood the fire.
This is so nasty.
Picking up all that water.
Lovely.
What's happening?
I just somehow burnt myself.
I don't understand how that happened.
Damn.
Bouncing burst.
Wait, is this like a three per... no, it's one spell per cast.
But why does it shoot two?
Wait a minute.
Huh?
Wait, I don't understand.
Why does that shoot two of them?
I click once.
It's like it splits off into two.
I didn't know it did that.
Chaotic polymorphine!
Very cool.
Ow!
This bastard!
Give me more water.
Shit.
Bam, headshot.
Man, how much damage is this doing?
Wait a minute.
Three damage.
How is that possible that I just one hit that guy?
Hold on.
Let's see here.
Is that a campfire?
Oh, no.
Yeah, cooked meat.
Lightly cooked meat.
I guess it could be a corpse on fire.
Oh.
Hello.
What's going on here?
So, do I put something in here?
Look at that.
Is that gonna do anything?
What if I fill it with this?
Like, what is this little structure here?
You see that?
Fill it up completely.
Okay.
Nothing happened.
Oh, maybe it's an empty potion.
Pick it up now.
So, it has a red symbol on it.
That could be the kivaskivi, maybe.
Maybe I put the fire rock in here when I find it.
Hmm.
What else could I try and put in there?
It's so weird when you move so slow, but you go up so quick.
It's very uncomfortable.
Either you go quick and go up quick, or you go slow and go up slow.
Otherwise, it feels completely off.
You know?
It's like having a different X and Y mouse acceleration in shooters.
It's the worst thing ever.
It's kind of similar to that.
Look at that.
It did six damage.
Why is this doing... I don't understand this wand.
I feel like I'm missing something very basic about the wands in this game.
Because look at this.
This wand says one spell per cast.
So, if I click this once, it should shoot this one, which is a very bouncy projectile.
Sure.
I click once.
Okay.
That works.
That was one.
Hold on.
Let me try again.
See how it sort of splits?
Maybe it's just because the Castile is so small that me clicking the button, I need to click it super quick.
Otherwise, it won't work.
Dude, Phlomoxium.
I remembered my lesson.
Maybe that will work with the barrel I found.
Oh, here's another one.
Oh!
Oh, wait a minute.
Do I need to also fill that with oil?
Hold up a second.
Do I have any oil?
I don't have any oil.
Let's find some oil.
Holy shit!
That guy had a wand and I just saw my own death.
But then he exploded.
I want that wand.
Come here.
Actually, let me water it.
Is that an enemy?
Where'd the wand go?
Oh, come on fire.
Get out of here.
TNT.
It's not actually great.
I don't like it.
Nope!
Okay, let's go find some oil.
Polymorphine.
Kill them all.
Oh, maybe I need to take the oil from here and put it there.
There's something odd about this.
Right?
Hold on, I'm going to try this actually.
I'm not... Oh, I should be careful with the bomb because that's going to burn this oil.
How am I going to do this in the best way?
That does not cut through.
Hmm.
Let's try and find some oil somewhere else.
Yo!
Oh, watch this, watch this.
Shit.
Oh, I didn't mean to do it like that!
That was such a fail.
I was going to goddamn kick the minecart into his face.
That was the plan.
Hey, miss.
And it backfired and he hit me in the face.
That's really bad.
Did not enjoy that.
Actually, I did.
I got to say, I actually did enjoy that.
But you know, I also didn't.
Oil?
Sir?
I'm basically going to take it... So, here's the plan for today.
Experimentation.
I'm not going to try to win anything.
You know, I am going to experiment with everything and everything.
Oil!
Here we go.
Let's get rid of flammoxium because who the fuck wants that?
Can I drink it?
I can.
Well, let's not.
Please drain down there.
That's perfect.
Also, I'm sort of confusing myself in the process, but that's okay.
I wonder if this is made on...
the basis of those mushrooms, you know?
Tripping balls.
By the way, the whole tripping ball shit.
I already forgot about it.
What the fuck happened there?
I kind of want to go back and see there was some kind of text.
Very intriguing stuff.
Let me get rid of this first.
So, no more confusion.
And then we take this one.
Yups.
Oil it up.
Oh, I'm taking damage.
I was drowning in oil.
As you do.
Kind of want to get high again, you know?
Something happened for sure.
Text came up and everything.
Okay, it was just to the east, I believe.
If this actually does something...
then I'm going to be even more in love with this game.
If this actually does something, no.
Okay, predictions.
I think it does something.
Say yes if you think it will do something or no.
I mean, if you know it will, don't say anything, of course.
Oh, it's not looking good already.
I'm balancing the world.
Everything is balanced.
Holy shit.
I can't believe it.
Oh, look at this wand.
It looks like a...
Oh, it has a name.
Rusu.
I bet you that means rose.
Because look, it looks like a flower with thorns on it.
That is fucking awesome.
Are you kidding me?
Thank you.
Okay, dude.
Dude, I need to look for stuff like this everywhere now.
I don't even know how many times I must have missed this before.
It never occurred to me.
You know?
I mean, I was just focused on fucking not dying.
But now I'm like... I mean, I'm still dying, but...
I'm less focused on not dying.
I'm more focused on other things.
There's flammoxium there.
This game is amazing.
I fucking love this game.
What can I say?
How does it keep getting better?
What's that?
Polymorphine?
Okay, let's see here.
I have two bombs.
I actually have these.
Does that actually dig?
Let's try.
It sure does, I think?
Wait a minute.
Yeah, it totally does.
That's awesome.
Fuck yeah, man.
Oh, man.
Oh, I get this feeling with this game where...
I feel like I've only scratched the surface still, you know?
I love that feeling.
That's steel and that's a fire symbol.
This is a trap.
Let's be careful here.
I guess I set off the trap.
Boink.
There we go.
Burn it all.
Porta!
Look, six damage.
I think it's because it bounces so quick and then it does damage twice.
Very odd.
Works for me.
All seeing eye.
I know what I'm going to do.
I know exactly what I'm going to do.
It's time to cross off one of my objectives today.
Maybe I get rid of my bombs.
No, I get rid of this one.
Do I get rid of that one?
Hold on.
Two slots.
Yeah, I get rid of this one.
And then we put this as my damage wand.
We're going to go reveal a certain area.
I think you know what I'm talking about.
Full on water.
I love the music kicking in when something badass happens, you know?
Like me finding that wand just now.
Like the game knows.
That I would like to have a celebratory atmosphere.
Okay, so look at this.
Look at that.
Let's pay fucking attention to the world now.
There's totally something here.
Right?
Will a wand appear here if I do something?
It says four.
Four what?
Is there anything around it?
Let's check.
There's water above it.
Two steel beams on either side.
Maybe if I get rid of both steel beams something will happen.
Wait a minute.
Get rid of this.
Mix that shit.
Hmm.
Okay, there's a lamp in there.
Maybe I need to set it on fire.
Or something.
Oh yeah, look at this.
I love turning the fucking green stuff into blue stuff.
It's actually one of the most satisfying things.
Look at that.
So fucking cool.
Turn it all.
Oh, here we go.
Oh, there's nothing down there.
But watch.
How's that not hitting the lamp?
Maybe it's not enough speed.
It sort of slows down in the oil.
Hmm.
Okay.
Anyway, so there's something going on here for sure, right?
But let's check that out later.
Ah, wand!
Oh, is that a... No, that's like...
It is a trap.
But that, my friends, is...
I think electricity?
Let's fuck it up.
Let's use our rose.
Yeah, get rid of all of it.
While that's happening, let me go up here.
I think I already went this way actually, but...
Whatever.
Oh yeah, I did.
That's the flamoxium incident.
The F.I.
We don't talk about that.
Should never have brought it up.
Man, this wand is actually nuts.
It's a great starter wand.
Some of them randomly hit that guy.
Just fire.
Ah, no.
No, thank you.
Okay.
Let's pay more attention here.
What else could be going on?
See, this looks mysterious.
Polymorphine.
Is there something in the polymorphine?
Do we need to throw something in here?
Let me actually try something.
Let me try water.
Sits on top.
Let's try levitation.
Sits on top of water.
Chaotic.
Oh, what if he makes chaotic with normal?
Chaotic is more heavy.
It floats to the bottom.
Interesting.
Okay.
I don't know why I'm saying...
Oh, there's a...
Oh, I already checked that wand.
Ah, okay.
Collapse the mind's time.
Honestly, can't tell the difference.
Most of the time.
I hate this guy because he turns everything green and I hate green.
Time to fucking fix the mistake.
Stop!
I'm gonna die here.
These fuckers.
Oh, yeah.
Burn, bitch.
You're made of flammable stuff.
That's right.
Have fun.
There we go.
Look at that.
Beautiful sight.
Oh, that's a mess.
I'm not gonna go for that gold.
Am I though?
Am I?
Where am I?
Nah.
Get it!
Nice.
I got it.
That's 50 fucking cash right there in the pocket.
The risk was worth it.
But only in hindsight.
It was not actually worth it before I did it.
Ah, there's a lot of oil there.
And that's my phlemoxium I put in.
Uh-oh.
But wait, we have...
There's water down here.
What if we lower him down?
What's up, nerd?
Dude, that guy just shot through the wood.
Come here.
Yeah, come here, buddy.
Yes, get in the water.
Have a bath.
That's actually amazing, because when they die in water like that, they don't spawn the lava.
That's super nice.
Gotta remember that one.
That's a nice trick.
We got froggies.
Can't even get through that, it seems.
That's a...
That's a sad fact.
Uh, let me get some water.
Always have a full water bottle.
So we can go full throttle.
Unstable teleportation plus water plus flammable gas.
Holy shit.
What a mix.
That's a cocktail, alright?
Burning meat?
What if I eat it?
Is that like a steak?
No, let's not eat it, actually.
Holy mountain.
I could do that.
But I'm not gonna.
I still have way too much HP.
We are not done.
Polymorphine.
I don't like...
I want the unstable one.
Well, I have the unstable one, I guess.
In fact.
Oh yeah, chaotic I mean, not unstable.
What am I talking about?
There's something down here.
Okay.
So much blood.
Man, I really wanna see if I can't find more secrets like that.
Like the oil barrel.
Let me get through here.
Sweetness.
Shit, I thought that would take me down to the wand.
Alright, fine, I'll use another one.
Actually, will I?
Wait a minute.
I forgot my mission.
I was to go west and use this over there.
Let's not forget that.
I wanna get down here.
Got it.
Water it.
There we go.
And that is a... actually a decent wand.
Except it's shuffle.
Hmm.
This is actually a great wand.
Do I want this at all?
I don't think I do.
Although the spitter bolt does eight damage.
It's actually nuts.
210, 552 mana charge.
This is actually not bad.
0.05, 0.43.
Hey, you know what?
It is shuffle though, that's the thing.
You know what?
We say no to shuffle wands.
We don't want that crap.
No.
No!
Don't fall for the trap.
Look at that.
Wait.
Man, that spell revealed a lot, huh?
Unstable teleportation.
I've been there, but I haven't gone this way.
I can't get through... you know what?
Let me use this.
Actually so cool.
I love this spell.
But the way to get up there, that was a bit annoying now.
I have to go all the way around.
Flammoxium.
How
much did I reveal with that spell?
I think it's more than your screen, for sure.
The fact that I could see the little collection of teleportation below the portal.
I didn't use that spell near the portal.
I used it quite a ways up from there.
Look at that little bridge.
A big bridge!
What the fuck?
Oh, man.
That could have been bad.
What the hell is that?
What?
Oh, it's just a piece of wood.
It looked like a mailbox or something.
I was a little confused.
Which is odd, because I'm almost never confused.
Like ever.
With anything.
Nice!
Easy axis.
That's pretty cool.
Let's remember that when we inevitably go back up here, because I will.
That's by the way the mission today.
Just like the last big run we had, I'm just gonna make a nice one, get some nice HP, and then we go back to the surface and experiment with things.
Let me see.
That is actually just teleportation.
Yes, it is.
And then if we go this way...
Oh, you know what?
Maybe I'll...
Maybe I'll take that.
Boink!
Burns up.
Thank you.
I could also go straight down to...
Not Heezy Base, but Snowy Depths if I wanted to.
From here, but...
Okay.
I think we're about ready.
No, no, no, wait, we're not, we're not.
We have the mission of to go west and use the All Seeing Eye spell.
Is it actually called All Seeing Eye?
It is called All Seeing Eye.
Perfect.
I have not been saying it wrong all this time.
I want to see what's going on over there.
You know?
It's a mysterious AF area.
If I can even get there.
It is possible that we are locked off.
Oh, wait a minute!
Not with this, though.
Let's get rid of levitation.
Let's put it down gently.
There we go.
Yes!
Unstable teleportation time!
So if we can't, like, look at this.
I pretty much cleared the entire area, right?
So if I use this now.
Do I teleport again?
Is it every, like, five seconds or something?
I think it's in the immediate area where I do it.
So I'm going to go west first and then I'll use it there.
I wonder if I can appear in the middle of Toxic Sludge.
That would be fucking scary.
Okay.
Why does this also look suspicious?
Look at this!
Doesn't this look suspicious?
Maybe I fill this with oil because of the red color on these?
Do I have any...
I meant blood, not oil.
What am I talking about?
Blood, blood, blood, blood, blood.
Chaotic.
Let me get rid of chaotic.
Put it down here.
Hell yeah.
Oh, that feels good.
There we go.
Very nice.
Gimme that blood, baby.
Actually, hold on, there's also a... one here.
Okay, now I'm not so sure anymore.
Hmm.
Man, this doesn't look very obvious, does it?
The other one was very obvious.
Well, let's try it.
Also, there was sort of a hint, right?
Because they had the bowl right next to it?
That had the oil in it.
Okay, never mind.
This was a dumb idea.
But I tried it, you know.
We're here to experiment.
Let's head this way now.
Grab some more water.
Very good.
Kind of want to try mixing liquids and powders some more.
Okay, so watch this.
Now I'm here.
Shit.
Now I'm back up here.
That's annoying.
Take me west.
Let me go down below instead.
Back down this way.
Yep, as west as we can get.
Is this as west as we can get?
Let's see.
Ah, okay, okay, okay.
Oh, look at that guy.
He's right there.
I can get in there for sure.
Yeah, I still have bombs.
I forgot about these.
Oh, that was easy.
Burn them.
Oh, yeah, you like the bounce?
I bet you love the bounce.
That guy has HP up the wazoo.
I hate those spells.
Oh, that hurt.
Oh, yeah, look.
Oh, it's gonna.
Yeah, yeah, it's gonna lightning me.
Get the fuck out of here.
Holy shit.
Exactly.
I remember picking that spell up last big run.
Hey.
Fucker.
How are you not dead yet?
I hit you for like a million.
Can you can you hit himself?
I wonder.
Got him.
All right.
Not bad.
Frogs.
Shit.
What the hell?
Oh.
Oh, man, we're losing HP rapidly here.
We need to be careful.
Burning frog.
Too fucking bad, huh?
I will go up here first.
I will absolutely cleanse this entire hemisphere.
Oh, my God, I I was just sitting there taking the hit.
I'm playing terribly.
And now all of this green stuff.
No, man, I hate that.
Mix it.
Very good.
How's that?
OK, we're fine.
Another wand.
With a magic missile.
Actually better than this.
I'll take it.
I will indeed.
We can fuck these guys up now.
Oh, wait, we can't get through here.
But we can, though.
We cannot, though.
Dang, actually, we can, though.
This is going to be a bit dumb, isn't it?
That was risky.
Hmm.
Let me go around.
And those roots of the tree, huh, they are resistant.
We think that was made of wood.
But maybe it isn't.
Here's the place.
I made it.
Oh, wait, what?
Oh, wait a minute, did I try this once?
I feel like I have memories of trying this.
No, no, I was here with a rock last time and that worked.
I had light on it.
God damn it.
Shit.
OK, now we know that.
Or do we?
Just murder everything, please.
Nice.
Actually, that's a sweet bomb.
Really good at taking out enemies.
You know what, I think it's time we head in here.
Yes, let's go.
Very good.
Uh...
Oh!
What's happening?
Take the health.
The fuck was that?
Huh?
I'm scared.
Oh, wait, what?
What's this?
Kills to mana?
No.
Oil blood?
You bleed flammable oil butter?
Ooh, that would be a good one to take.
Extra perk!
From now on, you will find an extra perk in every hole.
Yes!
Yes.
The earlier, the better with that one, right?
Fuck yeah.
Let's see here.
Uh...
Oh, the rock.
Well, that's going to be useless unless we have infinite rocks, right?
Plasma cutter, I want that for sure.
Bomb, maybe, yeah.
Spitter bolt with timer.
Hold on.
Let's see what we got.
Let's just see these ones here for a second.
So we have...
bouncing burst.
Let me try this real quick.
Yeah, that's just the way I remember it.
But that thing is going to be really dangerous.
I don't have a lot of HP.
And I need to be super careful with that one.
I really need to think before I use it.
It will kill me.
Uh, spitter bolt with timer.
Before I take that...
Let's see.
You know what, I think I want that.
And that.
Because then, this is actually a decently sick wand that I have here.
You know?
Actually, this is also a sick wand.
If I now do...
What if I just do two of these?
Okay, it's not that great.
How about that?
I guess that's pretty cool.
But not super cool.
I think I want this as well.
Nice to have, right?
Triple scatter.
Kind of useless here.
But it could be nice and...
Ah, this is a shuffle wand.
Non-shuffle, non-shuffle, both shuffle.
Okay.
So I think in the shuffle wands, I want to put my plasma cutter.
You know?
Because it doesn't matter where that goes.
It doesn't matter if it's shuffle.
0.05.
Let's just take something shitty like that one.
This is my plasma cutter.
Let's see if it's actually any good.
Yeah.
I need to be able to spam it.
Pretty good.
Let me actually see this one.
Actually, that's better.
Yeah, I'm using that.
That is my plasma cutter.
It has been decided.
Then we have this guy down here.
What should that be, I wonder?
We could have rocks.
You know what?
I'm going to buy it in case I find homing later.
And I get infinite spells.
Because that would be a great wand to just have.
I have seen the lights with that.
Okay.
Get that as well.
In fact, get everything.
Why the hell not?
It costs so little money.
And I have a lot.
Now, the shuffle one.
What if we just put a bunch of these in here?
Is that even any good?
Let's see how that feels.
Like it has such a small castile.
That...
Oh, the castile is even being reduced.
Using the bouncing burst.
That it just shoots them so quick.
So the thing that's limiting this wand a lot is the recharge time.
It's basically shooting all of them at once.
Like, it technically isn't.
But you know, it feels like it is.
Like 15 damage per shot.
So that's like, well, 3 times 5.
It makes total sense.
It's actually just shooting all of them at once.
So can I reduce...
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Oh, it's a shuffle wand.
So we can't do what I just thought of doing, but that's fine.
Maybe I just use this here, you know?
Keep it simple.
Just have some magic missiles here.
It's not the worst.
And then in this one down here.
Only a capacity of 2, so that's not great.
But can we make it great?
Is this even good at all?
Or does it suck?
You know?
How much damage is this?
It's not bad.
It's honestly a good amount of damage it's doing.
How about that?
So wait.
Let me see the board.
Yeah, it's just shooting both.
Okay.
Just have to make sure there.
So if I use these two.
How much damage?
It's not, it's 6 damage.
It's terrible.
But if I do this suddenly.
What it does is it shoots the bouncing burst, but then it shoots the spitter bolt with timer.
And after a certain time runs out, it's actually going to shoot this one as well.
So it actually shoots an extra spell.
Watch.
I'm going to show you.
I'm 100% right.
You see, it actually, it's hard to say, but in between there's like a little.
It does shoot a bouncing, it's hard to see, but it totally is there.
Look.
You see how it changes?
It happens so quick.
Why can't I see it?
So it's basically shooting three spells instead of two spells is what I'm saying.
If you slow down, slow that down, you can totally see it.
Good amount of damage.
But what about spark bolt instead of the bouncing burst?
It's a little less.
Because it doesn't bounce, I guess.
Let me just try this.
Terrible.
I like this.
It's a good amount of damage.
It's not bad at all.
Let me try something else then.
If I do this with that and that.
Even better.
I like that a lot.
So maybe we change this one to become something completely different.
By the way, how much is this?
The only issue is, this is like a short range want now.
Because of these two.
But let's do one of each, huh?
Maybe that's too chaotic, you know?
Does that feel good?
Maybe.
It doesn't feel amazing.
If I do that.
Too much scatter.
Too much scatter, for sure.
I like this.
Then we have the digging wand.
No, this is actually a digging wand.
In this one, we're going to have magic missile.
And how about we also add in some...
No, that's fine.
This can be our vision.
Why not?
Yeah, let's rock with that.
I like it.
I'm going to save this spell refresher, I think.
I don't need it right now.
Cool!
Let's get the fuck out of here.
You know what?
Watch.
I have an idea, I have an idea.
We are going to do this.
Oh wait, this is not going to home anymore.
Maybe this is fine.
We may actually die here.
We may die here.
Let's put this here.
No, it's random.
That's bad.
It's bad.
I'm going to dig myself out of here.
And I'm going to make the gods angry.
Let's see if we can survive it.
Oh shit.
Yeah, they are angry.
Whoa!
He came fast.
Oh no, I went up here anyway.
I'm an idiot.
I'm totally going to die.
Fuck me.
I'm an idiot.
I thought I had more time before he arrived.
No!
I can't... Okay, but you know what?
I think I've confirmed something, by the way.
When you exit... Hold on.
F11.
I can't see the start.
That's too bad.
Anyway, when you exit, the trigger point is actually when you rise up somewhere.
You know, I think I discovered this last time as well, actually.
I kind of forgot, but...
It's not actually when you get up there and go to the right.
It's when you move up.
You know?
Just remember that.
When you move up... Important.
I can do this now.
Stand here.
Almost made it.
Hold on.
Maybe I can give myself a bit of boost here by shooting.
Is that actually... That's not helping at all.
Maybe do another one.
Yeah!
There we go.
Man, it is raining.
I have water bottle?
Good.
Water bottle is good.
Dude, I have died so much today.
It's insane.
I haven't even gotten close to doing any of the things I wanted to do.
I mean, I did discover a bunch of new stuff, I guess.
I did the whole oil thing, right?
Oh shit, almost hit myself.
That thing just rolled down the hill.
Bruh.
Oh my god.
Oh, look at the recharge on this wand.
That's terrible.
That's gonna take a while.
What is going on here?
Let's get it!
Man, I have to destroy quite a lot more for that to fall down.
Unless I can get up there.
I don't need it to fall, right?
Like, look there.
Now we wait a bit.
Actually, we don't wait.
We just go.
Heh!
Almost.
Okay.
I wonder if the shooting this fireball will give me momentum.
Let's see.
Oh yeah, totally will!
Very nice.
Okay, now I go up here and get some money.
This is a great start.
It's a good start.
Boink!
Oh no!
Brixy ice!
Reward me!
Yes, turn it into gold.
Beautiful stuff.
This is the ideal beginning.
Look at all the water here, because of the rain.
I wonder if that keeps raining.
Forever.
Down the hill we go.
Always try to ride that on the way down.
Very rarely do I succeed.
I think I have chosen not to anger the gods anymore.
It just doesn't seem worth it.
Okay, here's the thing.
If I get the perk that will allow me to have the gods look the other way, then I will do it.
Obviously.
If not, I'm just not gonna bother.
Unless I'm really strong and I have a homing rock, you know, then I feel confident.
Like that one time, I just did it and I killed the guy watching with the rock.
Man, he was just like, I've come to smite the mortal for thy transgressions.
Rock in the head, you know?
That's how that ended.
Probably not what he expected.
But that's how I need to solve that problem.
I think that's actually been the hardest-hitting wand that I've had yet.
Like, I've done so much tinkering!
And then a fucking rock beats everything?
You know, I understand rock beats scissor, but somehow it also beats paper.
Beats everything.
What is it with me getting these black holes?
That I can't use?
It's every time.
And when I say every time, I mean sometimes.
There we go.
Here, miss.
Kinda need to learn the names of these enemies.
Uh, some more enemies, I mean.
What the fuck is that?
White hole?
An orb of positive energy that destroys everything in its path?
Say what?
Yo, I like that.
That sounds cool as fuck!
The hell is that?
I don't think I should shoot it, though, because look at this.
Heavy spread, and it's shuffle, and it shoots two spells at a time.
It says it destroys everything in its path.
I guess that includes me.
So let's not fuck with that.
Let's wait until we get to the holy mountain and we can play with it.
That's what I think.
Although we gotta be careful, we may anger the gods using that.
Note to self...
Be careful.
Duh, man.
I just... You know what?
It's Friday, and I'm playing Noita.
Can it get better?
I don't think so.
Don't shoot me!
Wow.
Nice.
Also, you know what?
The shots that he shoots look like?
They look like orange or like yellow versions of the triplicate bolt.
It's the same sound, and it looks like the same animation, too.
Uh, I can get through here.
Boink!
Nice.
Uh, yeah.
Shit.
Heh!
We're fine.
Oh, mine is a dead end.
But that's gonna burn away, and I can get through.
Something just shook.
Shook me to my core.
Uh-oh.
Look at this!
I gotta rescue these hammers from the burning building.
Come on, hammers!
Don't inhale the smoke!
Don't do it!
He's crazy for going in there.
He's a hero.
Ah, shit!
Ah, I accidentally killed him!
Whoops!
I meant to rescue them.
I'm gonna get this wand.
But I'm currently very oiled up, and there's fire beneath me.
Seems like a bad thing, doesn't it?
Let's get rid of it.
Let me water myself.
There we go.
Yo!
Disc projectile!
I do like that.
Maybe I like it more than the spark bolt.
76... Ooh, that's not a lot, though.
Let's see, that costs 20 mana...
per shot.
And there's only 76 mana.
But mana charge speed is quick.
Let's try it.
Oh, yeah, that's amazing.
I love it.
That's my new wand.
Fuck that other wand.
I don't like the spark bolt, anyway.
I like it when there's a trigger on it.
When there's no trigger on it, nah.
Although these things can damage me, right?
So, let's be careful.
That is Akiva Skivi.
Blamoxium.
Nice.
Dude, 20 damage early on is actually wild.
Look at all the hamsters!
Like a little family.
I murdered everyone.
Fuck you.
It's my turn.
Hey.
You fucker.
There we go.
Yep.
Doing well so far.
Very nice.
I can even go up here.
You fucker!
Unreal!
There we go, eradicated.
I hate these guys.
They have way too much HP.
I hate the frogs, too.
In fact, there's many enemies in this game that I hate.
There we go.
That was scary.
Wanna come over here?
Nice.
Alright, dead end.
But wait, is it, though?
I could use the white hole.
What is the difference?
That each threw all obstacles.
That destroys everything in its path.
What the fuck?
Maybe the difference is that the black hole, let's say it hits an explosive.
It doesn't actually trigger the explosive.
It just eats it.
Sucks it in, you know?
Whereas the white hole just fucking destroys everything.
Actually makes it explode.
That's my guess.
Nice.
Is that the portal?
It is.
We...
Oh!
We have 500.
It's not bad, actually.
But, man, I haven't found jack shit down here.
I mean, I have.
I found some wands, I guess.
But I mean, like, there's no HP and stuff.
Where's all my HP?
Maybe that's a good thing.
Maybe it's still here.
I haven't found it.
And later on, I get a perk that will give me more HP per pickup.
And then I come back here and I rock the world.
You know what?
Yes.
That sounds great.
Let's save that.
We're definitely doing that.
I'm also saving this heart.
I know, I'm a crazy man.
Uh, spark bolt with trigger.
I do enjoy that.
Fireball, maybe.
Oh, let's see the perks.
What do we got?
Why does this open automatically when I get here?
I don't understand.
I did not click the button.
Freeze field.
Liquids freeze in your presence.
No.
No more knockback?
Chorecepts, fungal creatures spawn from the corpses of enemies killed by you.
I haven't tried it, so I can't knock it.
Yet.
But it doesn't sound very...
aligned with what I want.
I'm gonna click here.
Oh.
Personal plasma beam.
You constantly fire a devastating plasma beam, but you fire spells much slower.
I feel like that's not good.
Projectile repulsion field.
Oh, I've had this one before.
Most projectiles are repulsed by your presence, but you take slightly more project...
That's actually a great one.
Pinpointer.
Your spells fly faster and have lower spread.
And you have a handy sight line for aiming.
This one is actually amazing as well.
Dude, I'm having a hard time picking between pinpointer and projectile repulsion field.
I think I would like...
I would like...
Protectile repulsion field.
It's actually amazing.
It's so good.
It saved my ass so many times.
I could purchase light from doing it, because it's so cheap.
Now, let's see here.
Let's try this damn white hole, huh?
Oh, I can't even shoot it there.
Really?
Let's try it here, then.
Alright, I'm scared.
I am scared.
Oh, shit!
Oh, no.
Hey, you like white holes?
You like... you like white...
You like white holes, sir?
Holy shit, I'm destroying everything.
Come on, hit the enemy.
Hit the enemy!
Oh, I'm gonna die here for sure.
Uh, what's the plan?
Let's cut him up.
Oh, shit, I accidentally picked that up.
I didn't mean to.
Oh, my God!
Ah!
Fuck!
It's over.
Everything bounces off of him!
Oh, no!
Oh, I'm dead.
Hide behind the statue!
I'm not here.
I'm not here!
No!
Oh, my God.
I'm being saved by the projectile repulsion field!
I'm 4 HP!
I don't know what to do!
I can edit my once.
I can try and shoot him with a black hole.
Dude, watch.
I fucking knew that was gonna happen.
Oh, no, man.
Dude, I hate this guy so much.
Oh, man.
I think what happened at the end there, I shot the black hole, right?
It ate the statue, which was my only protection against the guy, so suddenly he had free reign.
So fuck me up, you know?
He was sort of puzzled by me hiding behind the statue.
And that in combination with the repulsion field really messed with him.
God fucking damn it, man!
I'm back in the mines again!
Today's not going well, is it?
It's actually a travesty, is what it is.
I'm playing very badly.
I'm making poor decisions.
Why did I try that thing down there?
You know, in my mind somewhere, I was thinking, oh, you know, if it's like a black hole, it's gonna eat through the stuff, and the gods are gonna get angry, but it's a white hole, so maybe it's different.
I don't know why I tried it, man.
I should have not tried it there.
It was a dumb mistake.
Also, why did it shoot it randomly in a random direction?
That's what I didn't understand.
You know?
There was no heavy spread on it.
I removed it.
So, what gives, right?
It always shot it in a random ass direction.
Not where I aimed it.
Very annoying.
Maybe the wand itself had a spread that was insanely high.
I don't know.
But it's possible.
That's my theory on that.
That wand had a very high spread.
Okay.
This bridge is very intriguing to me, actually.
So is this one.
This time, I'm gonna try not to lose any HP in the first level.
Okay.
You know what?
I'm gonna set a new objective for myself.
I'm gonna get, let's say, 600 gold and as soon as I have it, I'm out.
No more exploring everything.
As soon as I have 600 gold, I'm out.
Because that's enough for two re-rolls.
Maybe a bit more in case I need to buy something also, you know?
But it's around there.
And then I'm out.
No matter what HP I'm at, I'm out.
Because I can always go back later.
Maybe.
It depends, you know?
But chances are high that I can.
And you know what?
I want to go back anyway, so...
I will be working towards the ability to go back.
There's a wand for me.
Circle of thunder.
Sure.
Why not?
Let's use it to fuck some people up.
I wonder if I can electrify him by making a thunder circle here.
Have the water be electrified and fuck it, let's see.
Haha!
Hey!
Awesome.
That worked exactly as I predicted.
And it was instant too.
He just died.
I wish I could take this guy's shotgun.
And go on a rampage.
Good.
I keep thinking I have water on me, but I don't.
600 gold, baby.
That's the goal.
Just 600 gold.
What do I have?
I have bombs.
Okay.
Bombs are actually really nice.
Whoa!
He almost jumped at me.
I mean, he did, but he almost hit me, I mean.
Oh, that guy is sitting right on top of one of those things.
I need to replace my blood with water ASAP.
Should actually be one of the first things I do.
Do we have any water?
I don't think I've seen any.
That's too dangerous.
I'm going above.
The dripping fire there always gets me.
The hell is this here?
Uh-oh.
So am I going to shoot this thing right when I go over here?
What's going on here, guys?
You like that?
Blow that shit up.
Have fun, guys.
Come on!
There we go.
All right.
I kind of want that money, though.
Come here.
Got it.
Why did I do it?
I'm too greedy!
Actually, that's fine.
I blocked the blood anyway.
I mean, I blocked the fire with the blood.
Nice.
200 gold already.
Oh, nice.
A heart.
Beautiful.
B.A.A.
Fuck.
Those guys do a respectable amount of damage.
Nice.
So far, it's actually pretty nice.
It's going pretty well.
I haven't lost that much HP.
It's a good start.
What's going on here?
Is this mysterious or is it not?
Oh, wait.
Thank you.
Uh-oh.
Oh, shit.
I do not like that one bit.
He's bleeding lava everywhere!
Hey, fucker.
Crit.
Nice.
Got him.
Okay.
Only lost one HP throughout all of that.
That's insane.
No idea how I managed, but I did.
We've got hammerses.
Always a welcome sight.
I think they are the easiest enemies in the game.
Just because of their low HP.
I think they actually have an HP of 1.
Because I don't think I've had anything that didn't kill them.
Just blowing on them gently.
Kills them.
This kills the hammers.
Good.
Clean execution there.
Ah, here we go.
You want to dance?
All right, if you're just going to stand there, that's fine.
How are you not dead?
Excuse me.
How is that in real life?
Oh, come on!
What the fuck is going on here?
Dude, I hit that guy for a million!
How the fuck is he not dead yet?
Also, I'm dying now.
This is insane.
Fucking...
Die, bitches!
I'm dying to that one enemy.
Holy shit, I'm angry.
Holy fuck!
And still, I'm taking damage from him.
I wish I could say I'm angry and finished right now, but I can't.
Bouncing Burst is the worst spell in the game.
There, I said it here.
You heard it first?
What a terrible spell that does no damage.
God damn!
Of course, I'm blaming everything on the spell and not on me, you know?
There's a frog right next to me!
I didn't even see you there, sir.
That's not going to bounce the way I intended to.
Oh my God.
You know what?
I don't like this place, I don't like the frogs, I don't like the big green guys.
Nope, nope, I'm out of here.
I'm going to greener pastures.
No, I'm not.
I don't want green.
Blue, I'm going to the sea.
What the fuck?
Have
we had a worm?
What the hell?
Now this is intriguing.
Dude.
Hey, excuse me?
Where's this worm now?
I wonder what determines there being a worm.
Oh, hold on, there's a guy.
Wow, he died from one hit suddenly?
What the hell?
Oh, they could actually kill me.
They're going to kill me.
Thank you.
I'm honestly tempted to just go through that portal.
I mean, I just need a bit of fire and I'm dead.
What's that?
Levitation?
I'm going to take it, I'm going to take it.
I have 8 HP.
I feel like this run is already sort of RIP, you know?
Does it get any worse, basically?
I don't think so.
It's pretty bad.
I haven't even found any wands.
Actually, that's not true.
I found one.
But that's it.
Nothing else has been discovered.
Give me money.
Thank you.
I will go up here now.
I'm going to keep exploring until I have 600 gold.
That was my mission.
Maybe I won't.
Thank you.
What's going on here?
Teleport, yes!
Critical on...
Bloody... that's actually pretty good, no?
A lot of enemies are bloody when you shoot them because they bleed.
Chaotic polymorphine.
Yoink!
Now that I got that stuff, I'm going to go down.
Honestly, whatever.
I'm going in.
Is that an enemy?
It's not... we're fine.
Go!
We have just enough for one re-roll if we need it.
I'm going to heal.
Don't have enough money for most of these.
That's a lot of triplicate bolts.
Is that light?
I'm not intrigued by any of this, really.
Let's see.
Why does this open here?
I swear I'm not clicking anything.
Projectile duplication?
Spells have a chance to duplicate, but you're more vulnerable to projectile... no.
Angry...
Sir?
Please step away.
Step away!
Oh god, it bleeds that shit too.
Ugh.
Oh my god, it spreads.
What's this?
Concentrated spells?
You spells have lower spread and extra damage, but have increased castellae?
I had this once.
It was actually pretty dope.
I'm going to take it.
Because if I can... if I use the spread like this, it reduces it completely.
I may actually buy that because of that.
Yeah.
Now watch.
If I put this...
Let's say...
Oh wait, no, these actually spread per default, right?
So watch this.
This is going to be a completely straight line now.
That's crazy.
That is insane.
Look at the damage now.
That's a good amount of damage!
Yo!
What if we randomly put this in here?
It's not really...
Okay, let's try this.
Randomly put it in here.
It's all shuffle anyway.
Oh wait, of course, it's only bleeding.
Then we have a teleport.
Not bad.
This one, I don't like it.
This is going to be my... one less?
Wait a minute.
0.18, 0.38.
What if we do this?
That's actually almost just as good.
I think I like this.
Makes a projectile always do a critical hit on bloody enemies.
And when I hit them, they're going to be bloody.
Oh, they're going to be bloody.
I like it.
I like it a lot.
Let's just... let's see here.
50 to 10.1.
Yeah, it's definitely better.
Yep.
What if we change it?
Ah, but wait, the mana, the mana.
The mana is decent.
You know, it's not the worst.
That one sucks.
It's got to be this one.
Unless...
Wait a minute.
Oh, it's shuffle.
Never mind.
Yeah, I like that.
I like that.
That's my wand.
That's a good wand.
Then we have teleport.
Then we have bombs.
And the last one, we could put in this, I guess.
Why not?
I like it.
And I'm going to take this.
No.
No, I won't.
Because that's only going to give me two bombs, which is like, whatever.
In fact, I'm going to put this here and replace this wand when I find one.
Yep.
That is the plan.
I can always come back here and buy these, by the way.
So...
If I need to.
You know?
Get the spells here.
I can always get these spells.
So what do I have?
I have that.
And another spready thingy.
Okay.
Pretty dope.
I am not going to anger the gods.
There's still lava there.
That's annoying.
That works.
Let's see.
Hey, sir.
Fuck out of here.
Oh, that is annoying.
Yeah.
Here.
That's the trigger right here.
Oh,
I need water.
Wait.
No, I don't.
Look at that.
There's already water in there.
Mix it up.
Okay.
This wand is actually worse than I thought.
I was underestimating how bad it would be with the recharge.
Let's see.
What is this?
Energy orb with trigger.
No shuffle?
Definitely better than that wand.
So...
Wait.
11 damage.
Why is it shooting so slow?
Oh.
Oh, trigger, of course.
So, yeah, it's gonna...
Interesting.
So, what if I hit an enemy with it?
10 damage.
Gotcha.
Oh, this weapon is great.
This is a great wand that I have here.
This is the first time I made it to the second area today.
After two hours.
More than two hours.
Can you believe that?
I have played so bad today.
Oh!
Oh.
That's a terrible charge speed.
Let me see it.
It does do 13 damage.
You know?
But this one does have a double in it, which is kind of useful later on.
I think I want this more.
Yeah.
I have decided I want that more.
Okay, what you got?
A bomb man?
See ya.
I have to remember, this also digs.
It actually digs.
So, that means gold's not gonna be an issue, because look at this.
Oh, wait.
Fire.
Let's be careful.
That was a lamp.
Lamps are dangerous.
Also, I need water.
Fill me up.
Let's take all of it.
Nice.
Crazy thing is, I can also get through gray rock.
But it's super slow and it's not very good.
But this right here, I take that.
Oh yeah, for sure.
Low hanging fruit like that.
You know I'll grab it.
Hello.
Oh, you like shotguns?
Me too.
Now we're talking.
Sparkbolt will trigger and speed up.
I like speed up.
Speed up is good.
Maybe I'll just replace this one.
I only have one bomb in it anyway.
Yes.
Oh.
Why did the screen just shake violently when I picked that up?
There's a wand.
Let me...
Hold on, actually.
Okay.
I can't really get down there that easily.
Maybe if I go around.
Yeah, let's try loop around like that.
Let's circle back.
Take that expression.
Let's circle back to that.
Oh, look at that.
It's really fucking hidden in there.
I forget I have teleport.
Dude.
I need to remember that.
I could sort of do this maybe.
If I can get through the first layer here, it should be easy peasy.
Oh my god, but the mana.
The mana.
Oh.
The gray rock.
How good is it at gray rocking?
Oh, the gray rock.
Also, I should have gone through here.
I'm an idiot.
Look at that.
Way better.
Oh yeah.
That's how we're doing it.
I'm stuck somehow.
I'm not.
I think it loops up like this.
Oh, I have to go like that then.
That works.
This may seem a little silly.
Wait, what?
Huh?
There we go.
Oh man, this mana is killing me.
I need an ad mana.
Real bad.
Look at this shit.
I'm making it.
I made it, baby!
Now I'm just going to get through that last part.
Yeah.
I mean, that's a great wand.
I would have been so happy to find this.
I can't be mad.
You know?
The thing is, it's even better than the one I have.
Fuck yeah.
It's actually a better teleport.
Sure.
Pretty neat.
Also, I just remembered I could have just made a straight line and then fucking teleported through it.
Dang it!
Let's remember that.
Damn, that guy was dead already.
Hold on.
That is gold.
Yeah.
You did.
Oh, you did.
Oh, it feels good to have a wand that doesn't suck.
Oh, that's bad.
Holy shit, that's a lot of lava.
What is actually going on?
Whew.
That's scary.
Man, there's a bit more drop off than you would expect on this triple scatter bolt.
Or triplicate bolt.
Oh,
but isn't that also because...
Your spells have lower spread and extra damage, but have...
No, no, I was about to say it has lower speed, but that's not actually true.
It does have increased cast delay.
I wonder how much that actually is.
It's negligible, it feels like.
Alright, everything's burning.
Shit's on fire, yo.
And we got a wand, baby.
Fireball.
Hmm.
That's not bad.
No shooting?
Is that you over there?
Aw, this explodes after a while, that sucks.
I don't want it.
Nope!
Where's the shotty man?
Someone's peeing, goop.
Whew.
Man, precise movement so far.
Haven't lost a single point of HP in this level.
Oh, it spawns these fuckers.
I hate that thing.
That's lava central.
That's what that is.
RATS!
There we go.
A secret.
Look at all that lava.
Look how many there are in there!
What the fuck?
I don't want to go in there at all.
I reject.
Nice.
Fill it up with that.
And then we mix.
Grab some water.
Actually feels great to have a shotgun.
Who's up here?
I'll take a bit of that gold.
Holy shit!
Oh, that was close.
I'm out of mana.
That bomb hanging there scares the crap out of me.
Let's see what we got, baby!
Wait,
black hole with death trigger?
What the hell does that mean?
This projectile, water to poison.
Yeah, how about no?
Another black hole with death.
Triple scatter.
See, this one I would like now.
Because I have that perk.
Concentrated spells.
I will save up for this shit, definitely.
I definitely want to try the trigger on death.
That seems pretty dope, actually.
Imagine having a homing rock, right?
That also has a trigger on death.
So you kill someone with the homing rock.
And when that guy dies, and this is how I imagined, by the way, that worked with the trigger.
Then it spawns another homing rock.
That kills the next one.
And kills the next one.
That's a never ending fucking camelcade of rocks.
Sounds like something I would enjoy a lot.
The thought of it fills me with joy.
I've been here.
That place was no bueno.
I've been up there as well.
That's where I dug.
Let me get through here.
Okay.
Here we are.
What's this?
Portal.
And a bunch of sewing machines in the back there.
Lava.
Oh shit.
Hello.
What's happening?
Another wand?
Can I get up there?
I think I can.
Watch, I'm gonna do like this.
This is genius.
Oh.
Sir, I see you.
Hands up.
Holy fucking shit.
What's all this?
Oh, bloodlust.
A projectile gains a hefty damage boost but is able to hurt you?
Right.
Oh, the cursed sphere.
Crickle on oiled enemies.
Another cursed sphere and sawblade orbit.
I had this one before but I never tried it.
Triple spell.
I think I want this.
This sounds pretty dope.
I think I'll replace it with that.
Even though it's shuffle, it has all kinds of cool things in it.
That I want to experiment with.
In fact, the bloodlust, I think I'm gonna do it.
I mean...
Okay, I don't know.
I don't know if the triple good bolt is already able to damage me.
Because if it is...
It doesn't matter if I put that on it, right?
Okay, so that thing right there, let's...
Oh, let's be careful.
How did that just die?
There's no way it died from two of my shots.
What the hell?
I have no idea.
Did that guy help me kill it maybe?
It's possible.
Oh, look at all that shit in there.
You know what?
Kind of want to clean that place, you know?
Do we have the capability?
Should I try this?
Hold on, it's a...
Oh, it's a shuffle.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Nope.
Also, I'm sort of going in a circle here.
Ah, here we go.
This is new.
I see you there.
It's crazy how much better I am at the game when I have better ones.
It changes everything.
Uh-oh, a ghost!
Gotcha.
Yeah, yeah.
Nice.
That's lava right there, look.
That is so nefarious.
You can have a single pixel of lava and it will tidally fuck you up.
If you're not careful.
Bullshit.
I shot him and he bled lava that then flew through the air and hit me.
And then I was on a... on fire.
It's actually really cool that that is a thing that can happen, but it's also really annoying, you know?
Like, ah, fuck.
I can't believe that just happened.
Yeah, look at the ghost falling down on me.
Um...
Go up here.
Ah-ha!
Look at that.
Oh wait, how am I gonna... maybe I can just go around.
Let's not go too crazy here.
We must have died.
Yeah, there we go.
I'm slimed up.
Oh wait, I can't get in there.
Um... hmm.
Wait, there's gotta be a way.
I'm gonna do this.
And then I'm gonna start digging.
I'm gonna make a large hole.
And then I'm gonna teleport bolt myself in.
And we can grab some gold along the way here too.
What if I teleport down there now, when there's no more room for me?
I just won't go.
Okay.
That is good to know.
Come on now.
Ah, I hit gray rock.
That's bad.
I'm gonna get that gold.
Very nice.
And then we can go through here.
Beautiful.
Oh my god, I can go through here!
I'm a goddamn blind motherfucker.
Oh wait, I still can't get in there though.
Ah shit.
This is not going well guys.
Dang it.
Actually it is going well, I can totally get in here.
I think.
Hold on, let's get some mana.
Come on.
Do I have concentrated mana?
That would be really helpful right now.
If I see concentrated mana, I'm gonna pick it up.
Really?
Okay.
It won't let me go down there.
There we go.
Man, it's hard when you don't have a digger.
I don't have a digger.
This want better be amazing.
I swear to god.
Another thing I've noticed with this spell right here, triplicate bolt.
If you shoot it at an angle, it will actually bounce.
Even on stuff like this.
That's why it doesn't dig sometimes, because it bounces off.
We fucking made it.
Essence to power, increases and protect health damage based on the... I mean...
No, it's not that great is it?
Shit.
But I mean, we would have gone to bed really wanting to figure out what was in there, right?
If we didn't check it.
I don't know how to say that in English, but we wouldn't have been satisfied.
Now that we know, at least we can, you know, rest easy.
Not thinking of what could have been.
I think it's time we just go, man.
I think it's time.
Let's do it.
No way, we have 125 HP though.
No, no, no, we're not going yet.
We are, we are going.
Yep, and we're saving this HP.
Let's see.
Let's see the perks.
Lots of triplicate stuff.
Bombs, okay.
Faster wands.
All wands you're currently carrying gain a bonus of their Castilean reload time.
How about no?
More love.
Creatures become more friendly towards each other.
Does that include me?
Or is it just creatures between them, you know, because if they become more friendly towards me, that would be kind of cool.
Trick blood money.
Blood money is dropped.
When death is an accident.
I remember reading this before and I still have no idea what this means.
Blood money is dropped when death is an accident.
Who's death?
My death?
The death of my enemies.
Hold on, I'm gonna reroll this.
I don't like these.
Glass cannon.
Your spells are five times as powerful, but your maximum health becomes 50 and cannot be increased by normal hearts?
What do you mean by normal hearts?
Living on the edge.
Your spells deal three times damage when you're under 25 HP or 25% of maximum health.
Hmm.
I mean...
I kind of want to try this.
Am I crazy?
Five times as powerful?
Like that is...
That means...
That's insane damage increase.
But then I can't heal anymore.
I mean, I can't... hmm.
That is a... what's this?
Revenge tentacle?
I don't like any of these.
I guess this one is just a buff.
This one is not... yeah, you know what?
I'm gonna take this.
It's not gonna negatively affect me in any way.
It's only gonna be a positive thing.
If I happen to be under 25% HP, I do more damage.
Bam.
Right?
It is what it is.
Okay.
Uh, want...
All of them are sh... Okay, this one is not shuffle.
But don't get that recharge time.
That's horrible.
Hmm...
Oh, let's try this now.
Let's do this.
No, I actually need a better want.
I need a better want.
Point one... what is this?
Point one?
This one is... Hold on.
Point one three.
Ooh, okay.
Point six two.
But if this is a shotgun type deal I'm making here, right?
Maybe I should not care too much about the recharge time.
Five sp... spread doesn't matter because I have very narrow spells now.
I want this one instead of that one, I think.
Yes.
I have decided.
Let's put this here and that there.
And then we're gonna grab...
this one.
Hold on.
What's that?
Better one?
Point two two...
No, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Spells cast one.
Okay, perfect.
I have to double check that.
All of these are shuffled.
That's bullshit.
We don't want it.
Grab that.
And then in here now...
Let's leave that.
After a period of time you will be returned to where you...
Hmm.
How long?
You know?
Let's try that actually.
See, now I'm a little bit curious.
If I could go...
cast this, go through a portal, quickly pick up some health and be returned.
Would that work?
I have to try that at some point.
I want double spell here.
I want double scatter spell.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Yeah.
No.
This one there... Do I have enough mana for this?
Is cast 25?
Okay.
Then I want this one here.
So it shoots a double.
This is one of them.
The other one is a double scatter, which means I'm going to put boink, boink.
Now this motherfucker is going to hit like a truck.
Watch.
It's going to be some wild shit.
In fact, let's try without this first.
Damn, son!
Whoa!
That's what I'm talking about.
Now, with this...
Baby!
Oh!
Oh, that's lovely!
600 damage, baby!
Hold on, how much does this...
Like, let's say I do this as well.
How much am I losing here?
I lose a lot.
I guess.
Okay!
Well, that is badass.
I like it.
What else do we have?
We have... Oh, wait, we have a triple, actually.
Hold on a second now.
Wait a minute.
One?
Oh, we don't have enough slots for this, though.
That would be glorious.
Unless...
Wait.
One.
One, two, three.
This shoots that.
Wait.
Six?
Man, this is a sick fucking shotgun right now.
It's actually wild.
Yeah, I like this.
I like this a lot.
This is nice.
This is good.
I don't like these.
I will remove two of them.
I only need one of these, I guess, to play with.
Now, Cursed Sphere.
Cursed Sphere.
Let's try the Sawblade Orbit.
Jesus.
So, wait a minute.
If I put this here...
Please don't kill me now.
Oh, shit!
Oh, oh no, oh no, oh no, oh no.
I'm ready.
Bring it on, bitch.
Come on.
Where are you?
Oh, no.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Fuck.
Are you over here?
There you are, bitch.
You want sawblades?
Huh?
How about that?
Yeah.
Fuck you.
That's right.
Oh, I was so afraid of dying to this guy again.
Holy shit.
Damn.
This, this weapon right here is scary now, and you know why?
Because...
it looks like these sawblades almost hit me as soon as I shoot it.
You know, I don't know if that's a thing that it can do that.
But it looks so close.
It looks so close.
So I actually don't trust this.
I'm sorry, but that is too scary for me.
I think I would need one of those activate after a short period type spells.
Or a trigger, right?
I need a trigger on that to make it activate or it impacts.
Because I just, I don't trust that right now.
I'm too fucking scared of it.
That is simply too scary for me.
That's a nope.
But wait a minute.
Speed up.
I forgot about that.
Wait, where'd the statue go?
Statue gone.
Those sawblades are...
kind of crazy.
In fact, it's actually a digging tool.
If you think about it.
Can I utilize that?
Let me see the damage right here.
What was I trying to do right now?
Oh yeah, I was trying to do this.
So right now the damage is 675.
It's actually precisely 675.
Every time.
If I now do...
that.
Is that going to change anything?
So 378 without this?
378, okay.
So increasing the speed of this projectile does not increase its damage.
That's good to know.
Okay.
Oh, speaking of trigger.
I have trigger.
I thought I didn't have any.
I forgot about these.
Wait a minute now.
Wait a minute.
What if I do that?
Oh wait, this is a modifier.
Shit.
Oh crap.
It's a modifier.
And all my wants are shuffled.
That's so bad.
Wait.
I may purchase this.
I'm going to purchase it.
Yep.
Thank you.
And for my next trick.
Watch this.
We're going to be playing with sawblades.
Boink.
Oh no, it cast three spells.
But maybe that's... Oh wait, I don't have enough mana for this.
Oh, that's terrible.
Are you kidding?
What is going on here?
50 mana?
The hell is this?
That's terrible.
What if I do this, by the way?
I feel like that's going to be nuts now.
Wait.
How much damage?
It's a little less.
But I was kind of hoping this one would...
reduce the recharge time.
Because it's going to wrap around, right?
So two, one, two.
This is the second.
And that one contains two spells.
That one and that one.
And this one is going to cast another spell when it collides.
And what is the next spell?
It's not that.
It's this one.
Right?
Hold on.
No, no, the recharge time is definitely the one fucking things up here.
Yeah, whatever.
Just do that.
It's a solid weapon.
Can't be mad about that.
Now speed up, can I use that somehow?
Honestly?
Maybe on the teleport?
At least for now?
You know, it is kind of slow without it, look.
Look how slow this shit is.
Oh, is that the same?
Wait a minute.
Oh, it's shuffle.
Do this then.
Oh, that's way better.
I think I would like that for now.
You know?
Obviously I'm going to use this in another wand later.
But for now that works.
And then?
What else should I be doing?
Did I leave any spells in these?
I did not.
Okay.
This is fine.
Let's get rid of one of these.
Man, the saw blade orbit is...
Oh, you know what?
This would be great on that weapon where...
or on the spell.
That activates a little distance away from you.
If you remember, we found that once.
Oh my...
Dude!
What if you put teleport on that?
Dude, can you go through fucking walls?
Imagine.
If I shoot a teleport...
here...
and it activates here!
That means the projectile starts here, lands there, and I'm inside.
That would be crazy.
Hopefully I find one of those.
I want to try that.
I only have two wands that I actually really like right now.
I don't feel like making more right now.
Is that crazy?
These are both shuffle?
No, this is not shuffle, but it kind of sucks.
Maybe a light.
It's a modifier?
Let's light it up.
We can have, like, a little light.
Even though it's terrible.
Look at the recharge on that!
Yikes.
Nope.
No, thanks.
In fact, I just want to throw this wand away, because it's so bad.
Go underwater.
Yuck.
I like this more.
Do that.
And then...
Do we have a long-lived projectile?
Let's try this.
Maybe this could be cool.
How much damage does that actually do?
Let's check it.
This is the one that produces a rain cloud, right?
So what is the initial damage?
And then it does lightning, right?
Actually, it could be really cool to use...
Ooh.
Could be cool to use on an enemy.
Because then the...
Yeah, dude.
That's actually not bad.
Oh, wait a minute.
Speed up on this?
Did that go faster at all?
Oh, it totally did.
It totally did.
Maybe I do want that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
We can live without speed on this, you know?
It's fine.
We get some light instead.
That's cool too.
This wand...
Let's try this one.
We're gonna have this in here to play with.
That's the setup, boys and girls.
Let's fucking go.
Oh, and watch.
I'm gonna try something here now.
If the trigger is here, can I cheat the system?
I tried this once, but up here.
But look.
Ah, crap.
You can't.
The game is smart enough to see through that.
Up, babe.
I hear shotguns.
Oh, ho, ho, ho.
Get fucked.
Oh, you got fucked.
This wand is sick.
It's actually nice.
Found!
Hey.
This is the ultimate...
Whoa!
Nope.
That ice formation is actually one of the scariest things I've seen in this game so far.
It's the same level of energy with the wild propane tank.
Oh my god.
Fuck that.
Fuck that shit.
Hey, you there.
Man, I kinda wish I had one more spot here so I could put speed up on this.
Imagine this with speed up.
That would be glorific.
Glorific.
That's a new word I love.
What's up, guys?
Yoink.
You also want some.
Uh-oh.
I was stuck, man.
Or, I mean, I'm very oily so I couldn't move quite normally.
I was slipping is what I'm trying to say.
My mind is all over the place.
It's Friday.
Let's focus on that.
Shit.
Okay, long range.
This wand is not the greatest.
I do not enjoy the drop-off.
It's really, uh, it's too slow.
Drop-off too big.
No bueno.
But I love that it can do this.
Ah, shit.
Oh my, I'm taking way too much damage.
This thing is, it's a great wand.
But it's too slow.
So I need to play slower, actually.
I need to conform to the wand, not the other way around.
You know?
The wand should dictate my playstyle, not the other way around here.
Okay.
I feel like I've just reached some sort of, uh, understanding.
A deeper understanding of things.
And this will change everything.
We've got hands.
Shoot the hands.
Wait, why did that crit?
It's a hefty damage boost.
How much is it again?
Plus 33, damn.
Digging bolts.
And critical plus.
That's actually not bad either.
This is actually a solid modifier.
How come I never use this?
Hmm.
Maybe I just get rid of the return, even though I wanted to play with it.
I do like the digging.
Yes.
And formation bifurcated?
Wait, why does it have spread minus eight if it's bifurcating it?
That's confusing.
Whatever.
I really love the projectile.
Look of this wand here, though.
It's beautifully red.
In fact, this right here, the bloodlust, is actually making it red.
That was a rock.
Oh!
Way too close.
What if I kick this?
Okay.
Stop it.
Stop.
It.
Oh, God.
Satisfying sound, though, when you shoot this wand.
Satisfying sound and visuals.
That's what I'll say.
Okay.
I have cleansed the entire upper storage place.
I don't even know what's speaking right now.
I was about to say upper management, but that made no sense.
That guy had a wand?
Now he doesn't.
And no.
Can I get in here?
No.
Shit.
What about over here?
That's steel and wood.
Oh, man.
It's surrounded by steel.
All the way around.
Actually, not all the way.
I could probably, if I really wanted to.
Question, though.
Do I really want to?
Yes.
I do.
Come on, get rid of that little piece there.
There we go.
Now we recharge.
And now we should just make a little hole and we can teleport up.
There we go.
Yoink!
Can I get this through the wall?
Ah, not quite.
Triple a bunch of TNTs.
No.
That guy's going to release a bunch of fire when I shoot him.
So here's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to go down back here.
Oh, come on.
What?
How does that not take me through?
Here we go.
It will not let me through.
There we go.
Nice.
Look at that prediction.
Exactly.
Phew.
Now we just wait for the fire.
That would have killed me for sure if I was in there.
I made the right call.
Got to grab that heart.
It's going to be a mess to get through here again, though.
Pee on it.
Lots of pee.
Urination.
Nice.
Oh, I'm on fire.
I'm not.
Got it.
That was a bit of a dig.
You idiot.
Why did you use that wand, huh?
Don't you know not to play with wands you don't know?
Strange wands?
Oh, my gosh.
Holy shit.
They just owned me.
I may actually have died there.
Like, the downside to this wand is multiple enemies and I'm fucked.
I always need to retreat and take them on one at a time.
There's simply no AOE on this wand at all.
Whoo!
I heard that.
I heard that fucker.
Oh, my God.
Another one.
Look at all the blood coming out.
He must have died.
I hate to say it, but I think it's time to go into the portal already.
That's steel.
That's bad.
Can't get in there.
Stop shooting at me.
Can I get in anywhere?
It's all steel.
That's a huge fucking tank of oil.
Isn't that oil?
Actually, I'm not sure.
I cannot get in, right?
It kind of looks like I'm digging.
But I think it's just getting discolored.
No digging is actually taking place there.
Magical?
No, I don't know.
I don't want to get in there.
Nope.
It does feel gloomy in here.
Naps the blook.
Is that you?
Up here.
Let me go around the right side.
Also blocked.
Oh, my God.
All right, fine.
The game really doesn't want me to get in there, huh?
Let me have this.
Why are you not picking up that wand?
Come on, I dare you.
I double dare you, motherfucker.
I know you want to.
All right.
Be that way.
I don't care.
Uh-oh.
Oh, shit.
See, this is one of those situations where I don't know what to do here.
Actually, I do.
I can teleport.
Oh.
Too late on that anyway.
It worked out.
23 HP.
One shot and I'm dead.
Oh, well, you know what?
I do more damage now because I'm living on the edge.
Why is there a bunch of brass here?
I'm so scared of a random shot exactly.
Something like that, you know?
We got to get out of here.
We got to find a portal.
It's simply too dangerous.
Come on, portal.
Where?
I hear massive explosions in the distance.
Can I get down over here, please?
Oh, shit.
Yeah, it goes down.
Oh, there's a wand, though.
Should I quickly check it?
Can I quickly check it?
I think I can.
Oh, no!
Water!
Don't kill me!
Okay, no, no, fuck this.
We're out of here.
Nope.
Holy shit!
I got to be careful of this.
Come on, portal.
There we go.
Get it!
Oh, my God.
Heal.
Damn.
This game is old.
Where the hell did you come from?
Did he go through the portal?
Actually?
Holy shit!
What's happening?
I'm being invaded.
Guys, come on!
Ho, ho, ho, ho, ho.
Yeah.
Okay.
Okay, man.
What's that?
A circle of oil?
Toxics?
All kinds of...
Warpcast?
Yo, what the hell's that?
Oh, no, oh, no.
I forgot about this.
Wait a minute.
Hey, hey!
What's up, man?
You remember this?
That's right, bitch!
Wait, what's this?
My perks are buried.
My perks are buried!
Never skip leg day.
Your kicks deal extra damage and knockback.
Yeah, let's go for a kick build.
That sounds awesome.
Can I get through this?
Hold on.
What do we got here?
Join with the goods.
Telekinetic kick?
That's not bad.
I do like that one.
Eat your vegetables.
You inflict more damage the more satiated you are.
But you start losing health if your stomach is...
Yeah, see, that sounds...
I guess it...
Hmm.
I don't...
So, I don't know what to think of this one, basically.
Never...
I don't like any of these, I gotta be honest.
I don't like...
I mean, this one is nice.
But I kinda want more, you know?
It's nice, but it's also a little bit...
Yeah.
Maybe I'll come back and re-roll those perks later.
I do want to try Warpcast, whatever the fuck that means.
Makes a spell immediately jump a long distance.
Stopped by walls.
Okay.
It's a utility.
What the hell does that mean?
Okay.
Oh!
So basically, no travel time on my spells is what you're saying here.
It's like instantly hitting its target.
That sounds pretty dope.
Dude.
Now I wish I had the pinpointer.
You know?
I mean, I can always just aim my cursor at the enemy, like, there.
That is actually...
That's crazy.
Wow!
Okay, but...
Then I lose this, right?
But the thing is, do I really need 600 damage?
Or is 370 already good enough?
You know?
Let me see what else we got here.
Uh...
Electric torch?
How about no?
Don't like that.
Firebomb.
Man, I don't like...
I don't like my setup here, man.
I don't have that good things, you know?
I feel like it's not that great.
Kinda just wanna put this on here and YOLO.
Because it kinda looked like it didn't damage me.
Like, when I shot this over here, some of them bounced back and nothing happened.
I'm gonna try...
Damn, that's a lot.
I wanna try and see if these actually damage me.
Oh!
Okay!
Okay, it's confirmed!
Okay, dude.
I think it was worth it, so just to check.
Because I honestly did not know whether or not that would damage me.
For example, the homing rock.
For some fucking reason, it didn't damage me, right?
So, who knows?
If this didn't damage me, this could be insane.
But it does.
Okay!
Now I know.
So that's a...
I mean, it's still...
I mean, unless I'm an idiot, I could make this work, right?
I just need to not stand in stupid positions, basically.
Critical plus...
15...
No, this is better.
Yes.
Okay.
Now this speed up...
Hmm.
Can I make something cool?
I mean, this is nice...
You know what?
Maybe I should do this.
Because 300 damage is still a lot for a shotgun, right?
And it would be cool to try and experiment with that.
Or I could do this.
That's honestly very good as well.
I lose a lot of damage, but that's fine, I think.
This is cool.
Because then we can put this one on something else, maybe.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I know exactly what to do, baby.
Watch this.
Wait, wait, wait.
What if I do this?
Yo!
Oh my god, that's awesome!
Look, it appears over there!
But it's not working, of course, because reasons... Why is it not working?
I guess because we can't mine through this.
But here, look.
Pretty dope, huh?
We just gotta make it mine faster, basically.
Faster, faster, faster.
What I'm basically thinking is, if I can sawblade orbit far away from me, then I'm happy.
You know?
So, if we do... Actually, yeah, yeah, yeah.
If we do this... Isn't that just gonna... OH!
Fuck!
Again?
Is another one gonna come?
Uh... Doesn't seem like it.
Wait, wait, wait.
Why doesn't that...
Oh, wait, I'm gonna hit it.
This one there and then... This one there.
Don't wanna use it on that, because those bounce.
Yeah, we don't like bounce.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
This one, though?
Is that... OH!
That's so scary looking!
What the fuck?
The bouncing bar is definitely not.
How about circle of thunder?
No, no, no, no, no.
That's stupid.
How about... I think I do like the digging bolt on this.
Look at that.
It is remote sawblades.
Is that actually working?
I don't know if... We gotta try that.
I think, like, it disappears immediately.
I don't know if it's enough to trigger a hit on an enemy.
We'll have to test that.
And maybe I do want this instead, because where we're going right now is actually a Heezy base.
And everything is close quarters there, so I think this is maybe better.
But then again, it will damage me.
But then again, doesn't this already damage me?
So, you know.
Whatever.
This one is cool.
I'm gonna try that.
Cursed sphere.
Maybe on that one I will put... Man, I don't even know.
This one?
Sure.
That's able to hit me though, right?
And I don't think I like that.
Don't think I like that.
Let's go back to that.
Actually, I didn't really try to experiment with this, but that's fine.
I think I'm good for now.
I will come back here.
And since I already angered the gods, I say, fuck the gods, it's time to get the fuck out of here.
How can I dig through here?
Can I dig...
Look at that.
Saw blades?
Actually insane.
Slowly but surely they're gonna cut through this bullshit.
It's so weird though.
Is that... Hold on.
It's still just called brickwork.
It's not like collapsed concrete or something.
This is such a weird... Can I do this better somehow?
What if I... hmm... bifurcate?
Wait a minute.
Warp cast?
Stop?
This is a modifier.
Modifier on bifurcate?
Two of them.
That means we make two of them at the same time.
Oh yeah, look at that.
It's better.
It's totally better.
It's digging, baby.
Honestly, cool.
And I'm gonna walk through here, man.
Oh wait, it's... I need to... It's not quite there yet.
There's still tiny pieces that need to be removed.
Is that enough?
Almost.
I'm so scared of standing close to this.
Let me just hit random places here just to get all the little spots.
This must look so silly.
Yes!
Yay!
I made it!
Awesome.
But now we only have 70 HP.
Luckily, this is one of the easier levels, so...
Huh.
What do we got?
In fact, maybe I'll not explore too much.
Go here?
Ah, these things.
Propane tanks.
They are scary.
The way they fucking fly around.
One of my worst nightmares.
Hello.
You want some of this?
How about you?
I'm running out of mana.
This is bad.
Oh shit.
Oh no, I'm sort of stuck here.
I'm drowning.
Well, that was bad.
That's that.
That's fucking that.
Wow.
Why did I jinx myself just then?
What is it about me jinxing, huh?
The jinx is real.
But honestly, let's be honest here.
That run was kind of shite anyway.
I feel like I didn't get the things I really wanted.
I didn't like my perks that much.
There was one perk I really liked, the concentrated spells one.
That was a nice perk.
But the other ones, honestly, I, you know, I wasn't quite happy with everything.
So I think this is actually for the best.
Probably just Copium.
But at least I'm aware of it.
You know, I have self-awareness about that.
Polym... is there anything down here in this?
No, it's just a big vat of polymorphine.
I don't know why I suddenly take on this Southern accent or what I believe is a Southern accent when I say those things.
I can definitely crystal my way in here.
Boink!
This guy's on fire.
We love to see it.
And he's also drunk.
Why is he drunk?
Excuse me, sir.
Why are you drunk?
Please stop burning.
It's because he drank all that whiskey.
What just happened there?
Whatever.
Get the fuck out of here.
That whiskey is flammable.
Oh wait, it was a barrel of whiskey, wasn't it?
What happened?
No, no, no.
Come on.
Get... Oh, a chest.
What did I get?
What the fuck?
What did I just get?
What?
A red symbol appeared and that's it.
That's weird.
I have no idea what just happened.
I don't even know what the... if there was a message that appeared.
I must have missed it if there was.
That guy's swimming in acid somehow and not taking damage.
I guess they don't take damage from acid.
I don't like when the dogs are on the move like that.
Hey.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Oh wait, I have chaotic poly... you know what?
I am now a mage that can throw that.
Pretty dope.
Actually kind of nice.
I kind of want to try that.
Oh.
What can I do?
What is my ability with this?
Am I damaging enemies?
I don't understand what that effect is around it.
You know?
Like, it doesn't seem to do anything.
It's a bit odd.
Chili egg.
Okay, hold on.
I just realized something.
This is called a chili egg.
Maybe I need to bring it to a chili region.
You know?
Maybe there's like a pedestal or an altar or something in some kind of snowy region where this egg goes.
It belongs there.
You know what I mean?
Or it's just a fucking egg containing something.
And if I hatch it, that thing will be on my side because usually they have like pheromone stuff on them when I release eggs, right?
What is in here?
Nothing.
Okay.
All right.
It's too quiet around here.
Oh, fuck.
Sometimes the explosions really shock me.
Gracias.
Look at all the hammies.
Look.
Oh, shit.
Oh, wait.
Never mind.
They don't only have one HP.
They have more than three, I guess, because they don't die from this.
Or do they?
I'm actually not sure.
Sweet.
Someone's throwing dynamite.
It's Barney.
Hey, come on now.
Stop it.
Where did he go?
Let's chase him.
Oh, we don't have water.
Remember that.
Oh, that was close.
Hey, miss.
Okay, watch this.
I'm so sorry, buddy.
I'm so sorry.
It was fun.
All right.
Here's water.
I'm going to grab it.
Fuck the chaotic polymorphine, even though I love it.
You know what?
I'm starting to think that these eggs may be a utility thing.
Similar to Kivaskiva or whatever the name is.
If I throw it in here, is it going to freeze the water?
No.
All right.
But we do know there's these items that have fire on them and some of them are chilly.
I think that will actually freeze the water.
Good.
Man, wow, that hit him.
Luck is on my side.
Ooh, the fire.
Not grabbing that gold, I'm playing it safe.
What's that?
Polymorphine?
Nice, nice, nice, nice.
It's going surprisingly well.
Oh, look at that gang up there.
I could get in there.
Do I, though, want to?
Worm pheromone.
I guess if you release a worm, you know, and then you put worm pheromone on someone, maybe that will just fucking make the worm a tag light guy.
Or maybe it's a way to make worms friends.
I'm not sure.
I don't even know how I would test that.
I guess I would try and pour it on myself and release a worm.
See what happens.
Oh, shit.
That guy came out of nowhere.
Fucking knew that was going to happen.
Blow everything.
Nice, nice, nice, nice.
More worm pheromone.
I'll take it.
What the hell happened here?
Why is this all look exploded?
Oh, no, not that guy.
Oh, wait, we can actually kill him because we have magic missile.
Fuck you.
That felt amazing.
That's right.
That's how we do it.
Ha ha.
I guess I could just could have just left him alive.
Oh, oh my God.
Stop it.
Ah, I'm wasting all my spells.
Will you chill?
There we go.
Chill, Yolanda.
Frog.
Let's say hi.
Ha ha.
Actually great for that.
Yo.
I think I've been sleeping a little bit on these crystals.
Like, they can be really nice.
They do a lot of damage.
How much is it?
A hundred.
Yo, that's a lot.
We're doing pretty good on money and portal is right there.
It's tempting.
Very tempting.
Why did that guy die from one hit?
He must have taken damage from someone else.
What I'm thinking.
Nice.
More money.
Oh, fuck you.
Damn frogs.
Oil potion.
Ah, sure.
I'll take one of those.
There's a frog.
I see you.
You like that?
Nice.
That's another portal.
Why did that not destroy any of this?
Is it all rock?
Oh my God, it is.
I thought some of it would be dirt at least.
Hey miss.
I thought we were friends.
And then you do me in like that, huh?
That's a broken wand.
I'll grab it.
I will grab it.
Oh man.
Oh shit, that thing is sliding too much.
Come on.
Wow, that did... Bro.
Oh wait, I'm dumb.
Whoops.
That was an access path right there.
Oh my God, look at all the hammers.
Ah, hey miss, stop.
That was scary.
I could have gone so bad.
I can get through here, I think.
What do we got?
Oh my God, that sucks.
I mean, but we don't have a fourth wand anyway, so just take it.
Now this one up here, the way to get in there is to go...
from this side.
Wait a minute.
Did I miss the little access hatch?
Oh, I didn't.
But we can get through here.
Perfect.
No more space.
Let's get rid of the worm.
What is going on there?
What is that?
It's wood.
It's weirdly vibrating.
Probably a physics error.
Of some sort.
Okay, I think it's time to go through the portal.
We have 600 monies.
That's the goal I was going for.
Let's find a viable portal, not surrounded by lava.
Should be... more portals, I think.
There's one right below me, I think.
Ah, I can... Oh, I can dig.
Maybe not very optimally, but it'll work.
And a pinch.
Let's go.
Sweet.
Alright, I'm excited.
Let's see what we got.
Wow, that one looks weird.
Look at the design on that.
It's like a...
knuckle thingies.
I used to punch people.
Now, that is the luminous drill.
That's a lot of bombs.
A question mark?
And a saw blade thingy.
Let's see what we got.
Why does it keep opening my spells when I go here?
Explosion immunity?
Extra wand capacity?
Extra life?
Oh my god.
I'm having a hard time choosing between that and that.
I feel like this one is very nice to have.
But that one is also really nice to have.
Ah, this one is going to serve me longer, I think.
I'm taking explosion immunity.
It seems too good.
Now, what do I want here?
Because I don't really have any wands that do any damage.
In fact, all of this is kind of crap.
This is the best, I think.
Like the spell, I mean.
Fire?
Is that?
Hold on.
Oh, these are just fire bolts with a question mark?
I forgot what that question mark means.
It's actually a lot of damage it deals, but it is limited.
That's the thing.
Hmm, I don't like any of this.
This is terrible.
But...
I think this is the best.
Let's grab that.
Oh!
She thought it was the small one!
Oh, that scared me!
Oh my god, I just saw death.
Nope!
I thought it was the small one!
Dang it!
Okay.
We're definitely not taking that one.
What do I want to use instead?
Maybe just fill it up with these.
That could probably get me through one level.
That's what I'm thinking.
Oh, I can't even buy this one!
I don't have enough money!
Oh no.
I have nothing.
I have nothing!
This is the worst!
Then again, it is just the second level.
It's not the end of the world.
Maybe I just want to do this, you know?
I'm debating whether or not I should heal.
You know?
I should.
You know what?
Better safe than sorry, right?
Because I can save my health stuff forever.
But if I die, it doesn't do anything.
So, let's play it safe.
Let's do the smart play here.
And heal up.
Now the bouncing burst, I mean...
I don't want to take that spell refresher yet.
Or do I?
Actually, I'll take it.
I will take it.
Because let's play it safe, right?
Like I just said.
Good news is, we have explosion immunity.
Okay?
Let's go!
The coal pits.
Now the damage I'm going to be using here is...
I guess that one, which is not great.
It smells like soil in here?
What did it say?
I didn't manage to read that in time.
Can I want to set fire to this?
Is there a secret in there?
Uh-oh.
Whoa!
Oh, this is not good.
This is not good.
I'm using my high value once here.
Oh, I want that so bad.
I can definitely get it though, right?
Oh yeah.
And then we do this.
That's definitely doing something.
It's not a lot though.
There we go.
Please.
Short range homing!
Not bad.
Remove explosion?
Makes the projectile no longer explode.
Huh.
Okay.
Maybe I will take this.
Let's actually try it.
What is the point of these again?
Summons an otherwise empty egg that casts a spell upon cracking open.
I don't understand this one.
Why is it not... Oh, do I have to crack it?
Huh?
Yeah, I don't get it.
That one is a bit mysterious to me.
Just a bit.
So my goal right now is to not have too many fights here.
Oh shit.
Kind of find some quick ones that I can discover.
Or just find some quick ones in here and then get the fuck out.
Because I don't really have any good weapons.
Oh shit, I used the wrong one there.
I used the wrong one again!
Oh my god!
I'm putting myself in the corner.
Get that shit out of here.
Uh, yep.
Fuck you.
Actually, I heard a portal already.
Holy shit, that's...
What the hell is happening down there?
What the fuck?
It's like a sea of fire.
And it's raining lava as well.
This is just hell itself, isn't it?
Show me the wants, show me the goods.
Yikes!
Oh my god!
I have no damage except this...
Only 9 charge want right now.
It's terrible!
Holy shit!
I'm leaving, I'm leaving.
I'm out of here.
As soon as I've used my 4 remaining shots, it's time to get the hell out.
Oh my god!
That almost fucked me.
Come on, hit them, please, hit them.
Okay, one of them died.
There we go, he's dead.
Oh my god, so much fire.
Go!
Just go!
Take that.
Let's see.
Energy spheres, what the hell is this?
A bunch of pollen, I think?
Uh, okay.
More of that.
And that.
Let's see the perks.
Never skip leg day.
Want radar.
You can sense nearby wants.
That sounds pretty intriguing, actually.
Freeze field, liquids freeze, no, I don't like that one.
I think I like this.
Yeah, but wait a minute.
We also need to spend some money here.
So, no, no, maybe I want to re-roll perks.
This one is honestly, it's also 50% off.
Like, the wand itself is actually kind of nice.
It always casts, I think, a crit on bloody enemies.
It's non-shuffle, it casts one spell per cast.
Small cast delay, decent recharge time, mana max is decent, mana charge speed is also decent.
This is a great wand.
Let's replace it with that one.
Let's see how this does.
I mean...
How much damage does this do?
Five.
But then...
Oh, a small floating projectile that homes towards nearby creatures.
I didn't realize that it homes.
Okay, wait a minute.
Is it homing?
Oh, that's actually...
That's not a bad amount of damage, I don't think.
I kind of like that, but you know what, let's re-roll.
I'm going to roll with this, I think.
Oh, what we got here.
Glass cannon, again.
Close call, you gain additional chance to deal critical hits as long as there are enemies near you, and critical hit plus.
I'm tempted to try the glass cannon.
Just because I have so little damage right now...
Fuck it, right?
And we're so early anyway.
Could be fun to try, I guess.
Oh, we actually have this, short-range homing.
We could put that on something as well.
Um, wait a minute, where's the one die there?
What if I take this?
Do that.
Hold on, so if this does five times damage, right?
That would be 15 every time I use that.
Ooh, that's actually not...
But 50 HP.
Oh my... I mean, it's actually only one-third of what I have now, right?
I think I want to try it.
You know what, today has been kind of a disaster anyway.
Can it really get worse, is what I'm thinking.
I'm doing it.
I'm fucking doing it.
Glass cannon time, baby.
50 HP.
Oh my god.
Your maximum health becomes 50 and cannot be increased by normal hearts.
Normal hearts.
But wait, what does that mean?
Does that mean it can be increased?
With...
non-normal hearts?
Whatever that is?
What the fuck does that mean?
Wait a minute.
Oh wait a minute, I'm immune to the explosion of this.
That's actually really nice.
That means I can go in close quarter and go nuts with that.
But do I want to go in close quarter when I have 50 HP?
They're definitely home.
That's a lot of damage they do!
That is not bad.
What if I do this?
Only one of them is gonna...
Yeah, look.
One of them homes much quicker.
If only I had a triple spell or something here.
Although...
Hold up.
One, two, three, four, five.
Let me... I have an idea here.
If these are all gonna be homing...
Yo!
Oh wait, do these do damage to me when I walk into them?
Ah, they do!
Oh, I lost half my HP!
Well, we tested.
Now I don't want that, I don't think.
That's way too... no, no, no, no, no, no.
That's bad.
I do like this though.
Oh, you know what?
Maybe it's better if we just do this.
Hold on.
How fast does this shoot?
It shoots quite fast, right?
So maybe it's just...
That's actually better, I think.
We can put this on another wand.
Like that one.
How much mana does it cost?
I mean...
No, mana is bad on this, mana is bad on that.
We gotta go with this one.
Let me see here.
Maybe I like this more.
It's a lot of damage!
Like, it is!
And I have very low HP.
Shit.
It's actually a disaster, is what this is.
Uh... hmm.
I don't really know.
I feel like this run is a joke.
Everything here is a joke.
Whatever, let's go.
Let's just try and rock this, you know?
See what happens.
We're going with the pollen, baby.
And we gotta be careful not to step into the pollen.
Because we have allergies.
A severe case of them.
Hey, that works pretty good.
Come on.
Show me what you got.
Are you kidding me?
Is that not gonna damage mechanicals?
You're fucking kidding me.
Wait, I'm actually already dead.
How is glass cannon ever a viable thing in this game?
It doesn't make any sense.
Everything kills you, man.
There's no way.
I mean, I started with 25, of course, but still.
I feel like glass cannon is...
the worst perk in the game.
Like, unless you are a fucking master at dodging everything.
I feel like this is one of those games where you just cannot dodge everything.
Unless you are a master.
Is that gold?
Oh!
Yo!
The digging is wild on this.
Excuse me?
Why is the digging so wild?
Oh, shit.
I'm actually already dead.
It's over.
Have fun.
See, while it's here, I'm scared of going near it.
Want.
Show me the goods.
Death cross?
Yeah, no.
I feel like that's certain death.
Guys, I hate to say this, but we got to find a portal and get the fuck out of here.
There's just no way.
Especially when this doesn't even damage these.
Look.
It does!
Okay, never mind.
Thank God.
It... what?
Oh, my God.
Okay, so they do not damage them directly, but the explosion does.
So what triggers the explosion, I wonder, there?
You know?
That's the confusing part.
This is so over, by the way.
3 HP?
Come on, man.
I'm pretty much done for.
Just release all of these and get the hell back.
Take care of them.
Let me grab that gold.
That's actually quite important.
Have fun.
Get him.
I kind of want a more long range homing.
Want.
Oh, this could be good.
Oh, the digging is real, dude.
That's something, at least.
It's actually really nice at digging.
Yes!
Yes, baby!
That's what I was wanting!
Explosion immunity?
That's what I'm talking about.
Gimme.
Yes, sir.
Let's see here.
Yep.
Awesome.
Bam!
That's what I'm talking about.
Let's fucking go.
I mean, I'm probably dead anyway, but...
One shot and I'm dead.
Oh, my God.
I am so scared.
Don't go in water with this, Fark.
Love of God.
Just go down.
Go down.
Did we make it?
We made it!
Just go!
Fucking get out of here!
Holy shit!
Heal up immediately.
Oh, wait!
Wait.
What?
We're at 60 now.
Okay.
I kind of forgot that this gave us 10 extra HP, so this is like a special one.
Alrighty, then.
Issue is, though, we don't have any money.
We are broke.
What the hell is that?
I think I've seen that before once, but what?
Is that oil cloud?
And it looks like something like that, right?
Levitation trail.
When levitating, you leave a trail of magical sparks that harm... nah.
Greed.
You gain double the gold per nugget.
Huh.
I am kind of in need of gold.
Protectile duplication.
Have a chance to duplicate, but you're more vulnerable to protectile damage.
Uh... no.
Definitely not.
Kind of want to save.
Kind of want to grab the greed, actually.
I'm so low on money.
You know what?
I'm taking it.
I'm a greedy bastard.
Is there anything here I would want later if I come back?
Maybe that one could be cool.
Uh...
And maybe the digging thing is also cool.
This...
Imagine having speed up on this.
This would actually be really dope.
Wait a minute.
If I do five times damage, this one is going to do a shit ton of damage.
It deals 125 already.
Wait, that's it?
Wait, what?
250?
Spells of five times is powerful.
How is that five times?
Something doesn't add up here.
Something doesn't add up.
I just need one of these, I guess.
Right?
Or is it bad?
Wait, what?
How fast does that shoot?
Okay, what if I do this?
Not actually... Oh, you know what?
I could put this somewhere else.
Better.
Let's try this one.
Even better.
But look at that mana recharge.
That sucks, so it's actually worse.
I think this is the one.
Although...
Not bad either, but I think this is the one.
Uh... Oh, hello.
Welcome to the party.
This one is actually the best.
That's fine.
Okay...
Formation Pentagon...
Wait a minute.
Uh, how does that work?
Isn't this instant?
Huh.
I'm not sure about that.
I think I'm just gonna rock this, honestly.
60 HP, let's see what we can do.
You know?
Uh, spell refresh, maybe?
Spell refresher...
Not really anything to refresh.
Nah.
We're good.
We're good, baby.
Let's go.
We're doing a shit ton of damage.
Kinda wish I had one of those double spells that could, like, shoot multiple of these lightning bolts at the same time, but...
It is what it is.
Okay, we're back.
The Heezy Base.
Let's not die immediately like we did last time.
That was kinda pathetic.
But, I mean, I think we actually had around 60 HP last time we were here, too, you know?
Because we lost a lot in experimentation.
See ya.
Man, electricity is great against these mechanical guys.
That's so important.
In fact, it's good against most things.
Then we have number three.
I'm gonna put that on two, I think.
That's fine.
I need to be really worried about water surfaces and steel, pretty much.
Maybe I should even make it a... what do you call it?
A habit to switch over to a non-electric wand whenever I just traverse.
And then switch back to my electric when I'm fighting.
Wouldn't be a terrible idea.
It's like trigger discipline.
You know?
Let me try this again.
Boink.
It's still decent.
Gimme that gold.
Actually nice to get a bunch of extra gold.
Fuck you, Ghostbuster.
So he's electrified for a short while after I hit him with it.
I wonder if this will electrify the steel sometimes.
Maybe he wasn't making contact with it there.
It's something I'm afraid of, like that, look.
It's electrified right now, that scares me.
You can tell I'm scared.
I'm actually very scared.
Shit.
Nice.
A sniper, huh?
You like that?
Bet you hate that.
Oh yeah, as long as you have a good wand, this place isn't that bad.
I mean...
Yeah.
I think actually this place is the place I've died least.
Funnily enough, I think the first area is the area I've died most.
You know?
It makes sense, I guess, because that's where you start out and that's where you learn the ropes.
Look at that wand right there.
How the fuck is this missing so much?
There we go.
Oh my god!
Makes a projectile release a cluster of explosive bolts upon hitting a wall?
With plasma cutter?
I think that's a bad idea.
But I will take it because cutting through things sounds awesome.
And I do need that capability.
Bye bye.
Now I just need fire immunity and I'm good to go.
If I'm just immune to all damage, the glass cannon perk doesn't matter.
Think about it.
That's galaxy brain right there.
The fuck did he just... was he holding a salami?
Hold on, is there a kitchen nearby?
What the hell is that?
Fully cooked meat?
Wow.
Oh.
Thank you for the meal.
I appreciate.
Oh, you wanna dance?
Oh shit.
I regret dancing.
I didn't mean to.
I'm sorry.
I'm kidding.
I love dancing.
I actually do love dancing.
I've got a dude here.
Watch.
Boink!
Doink!
You know, glass cannon doesn't matter.
If you never take damage, you know?
Hell yeah.
I retract my statement about it being the worst perk.
But I'm obviously just saying that because it's going well right now.
As soon as I instant die, I'm going to whine about it.
You know how it is.
And I can gain HP.
But it's just not a lot.
And maybe there are other ways, who knows?
Like in the game, to actually gain more.
So watch this.
I can dig.
Can I go through steel with that?
No way, right?
Ah, okay.
That would be crazy.
But there.
Not bad.
Dude, that's so good.
It's great for that.
Oh my god, this is a death trap.
All those explosives.
But wait, I'm immune to explosives.
What's up, dude?
Ow!
I'm not immune to fire, though.
And fire deals a lot of damage when you have 60 HP.
That's a big deal, yo.
Emilio.
If your name was Emilio.
Boink!
I see you there.
I can totally get up there.
Annoying homing right now, actually.
Oh my god, they are lining up to die.
Sweet!
Ooh, that's a...
Ooh!
Yep!
This is my favorite level, I think.
I just love the density of enemies and the close corridors and all that.
It's so good.
It's a lot of fun.
I actually have a plasma cutter.
But it also has a little protectile modifier on it that makes me deathly afraid of it.
That's why I'm not using it.
What the hell is going on there?
Whoa!
Don't go in there.
Alright.
Oh, hello there.
Come here.
Ah, let me kill that guy.
He's going to come back and haunt me later.
Exactly!
Every HP lost here is a big deal.
Nice.
Love this weapon.
Lightning bolt may be one of my favorites in the entire game.
It's so satisfying to use.
Shit.
Wait it out.
Trigger discipline.
Sweet.
Bye-bye.
All I need is cold resistance, fire resistance, toxic resistance, melee resistance.
I need all the resistances and then I am pretty much ready to go.
It's that easy.
There's stuff going on up there that I'm intrigued about.
Let's get the hell on in there.
Never mind.
That's boring.
What's going on here though?
Okay.
Wow, that actually took care of the explosive without exploding it.
Did you notice?
That's weird.
Oh, it's so good at digging through snow.
Like look, never mind.
It definitely explodes them.
Gotcha!
Ow, oh my god, 33!
Damn!
I can't take another hit like that.
In fact, I can't take any hits.
I'm so low.
This perk is nuts.
I retract my retracted statement.
This perk is the worst in the game.
HP, wait.
Hold on.
So this is not going to do anything is what you're telling me?
I don't believe it.
But some sort of curse.
No!
I'm not surprised.
Rip.
I'm sort of stuck here now.
That is just so sad.
Sadness overwhelming.
You there, sir.
You seem like you enjoy electrons.
How about them electrons?
You like that?
Any fire will kill me.
Boink!
Come on.
Oh, that's fire there.
I'm scared.
I'm so scared.
In fact, just release a bunch of these.
Let them go nuts.
It killed something, I think.
Is that guy alive there?
Wait, what the fuck is that?
Oh, it's a Kiva skeevy.
Ah, dude.
Where's the portal?
I need to get going.
I have 2,700.
That's more than enough.
There it is.
Go!
Holy shit.
Oh, wow.
70 HP.
70, baby.
What the hell is that?
Decelerating shot.
Why would I want that?
What's that?
Summon firebox swarm.
Glue ball.
Man, I don't like any of these.
I am unhappy with those.
What's this?
Extra item in Holy Mountain.
Oh, I thought it was more money.
There will be an additional item in every Holy Mountain you haven't discovered yet.
Huh.
I mean, that's not bad, but one more item when there's...
How many?
10?
This hardly seems worth it.
What was this?
Stainless armor.
You would take 50% less damage as long as you...
This one is fucking needed.
When I have such low HP, man, any type of help I can get, I'll gladly take.
Damn.
Okay, my weapon is good.
Weapon is good.
Can I modify my...
You know what?
Let me take that.
I want to see what it does.
Makes a projectile decelerate as it flies.
Okay.
Why is that good?
I'm trying to understand.
It decelerates as it...
Let me also change that real quick.
Why is that good?
If it decelerates, is anything more deadly when it's slow?
Is there such an...
Are we talking dune here?
You know, where gunfire won't work, but getting in close with a knife will work?
I wonder if there's enemies that have that exact dune armor type deal.
Because in that case, I would see the idea, but...
burst of air.
You know what?
Let me check this again.
I actually need to see exactly what that does.
Six damage.
A brittle burst of air capable of greatly pushing objects.
I actually slept on that description for a while there.
Let me see.
How long does it go?
It goes sort of far.
Well, not amazingly, but...
Oh, you know what?
Giga disc projectile with the decelerating shot?
Could be more safe, if you think about it.
Right?
Oh, actually, decelerating shot.
Oh, ten mana.
It does reduce cast delay, I guess.
But it's not a lot.
Formation.
I want to just have this, I think.
For that one.
Good old plasma beam.
You know what that is?
We will use it.
So, this is not actually a projectile.
I mean, it says projectile, but when you shoot it, it's pretty much an instantaneous arc.
You know?
So, I'm not sure how much this will help with that.
Oh, but here, look at this.
Makes the projectile release a cluster of explosive bolts upon hitting a wall.
This one sounds cool, in theory, on this one.
But...
I was about to say, if this releases fire everywhere, then I'm fucked.
It doesn't seem like it does.
I'm not taking damage from these.
Fuck me, man.
I take it back.
I have learned another valuable lesson.
That modifier... is bad.
I thought I would be immune to the explosive effect, dude.
What did I die from?
I don't understand.
Cause of death, meanest projectile.
What the fuck?
What is meanest pro- Wait a minute.
Progress?
Can I sort by searching?
Oh, that's the new one I discovered.
Let's see here.
Meanest pro- What did I just use?
I used...
This one.
No.
Yeah, this one, right?
Makes the projectile release a cluster of explosive bolts upon hitting a wall.
What?
How?
What is meanest projectile?
How did I just die?
I don't understand.
Wait a minute, what was the other one I used called?
It was the electric, this one.
Lightning bolt.
Unless it means my projectile, because in Danish it means...
Maybe it's like Finnish for my own projectile.
I mean, you killed yourself, basically.
Is what that death message is.
That's the only thing that makes sense here, because it's not actually...
It sounded like a spell name at first, you know?
Like, oh, meanest projectile, or...
Radagast, fucking...
You know, spark of lightning from the east, or something, you know?
Yeah.
Okay, well...
Honestly, that run wasn't going anywhere anyway.
With the glass cannon.
Let's be, let's be honest.
There's no way I would have gotten anywhere with that.
I can just imagine later.
You know, when I go back to the surface and I explore the pyramid and all that shit.
Where I take damage left and right.
How the fuck am I supposed to survive?
With around 100 HP.
It's just not gonna happen.
You know?
No way.
So I think this was for the best.
And I learned some lessons along the way, which is awesome.
So...
Get smarter every day.
Hey everyone, it's me Destin.
And welcome to Smarter Every Day.
Today I'm gonna blow myself up with a projectile.
And it's awesome.
We're gonna learn so much cool science.
Boink!
Hehe, wasn't ready for that one, were you?
Okay, same deal.
Let's say, actually, let's change the rules a bit.
200 gold is the amount we want.
Because that allows us at least one re-roll.
So let's say 300 gold is the optimal amount to go for before we move on.
Because that way we can also purchase some spells, if we need to.
So we can do a re-roll and we can purchase some spells.
600 is maybe a bit overdoing it, because it's kind of high.
You know, it's not that easy to collect gold in the first level.
It takes a while.
That's the new rule everybody.
And this...
Wait, what just happened there?
Why did he drop four gold nuggets?
Wait a minute.
Wasn't there a perk that gave...
money when death was an accident?
Is this what's... but I don't have that perk.
Is that... because that's the only thing I can imagine what just happened here.
That... I didn't kill that guy.
That guy died by accident.
And he dropped four gold coins for me.
But I don't have the perk.
I am so confused.
I am so confused by what's going on here.
Maximus Confusius would be my name if I was living in...
Ancient Italy.
Or Greece, I should say.
Or is it Italy?
I don't know.
That would be my name.
Oh my god!
Huerta!
You Huerta me!
Ow!
It's Huerta!
Ah!
That was close!
My goodness!
Uh, Barney?
Of course he would be hanging out near that barrel, huh?
That was a six shot just now.
I'm proud of myself.
Also, wait a minute!
We have swap potion?
That's actually okay.
That will take out fires.
So we're all good.
Hey, you there.
You like this?
Ah!
You hate it!
Which means I love it.
Hey, miss.
Good to see you.
Uh, that guy is not on fire.
He's always on fire.
I wonder if he likes swap.
Probably not, right?
Why am I even... should I even engage with him is the question.
Like, I don't need to engage with this guy.
I can just go the other way.
I'm gonna be the adult here.
And say, nope.
I do not participate in this little quarrel.
I shall go my own way and roll this boulder.
What the hell?
It's a huge boulder.
That's weird.
Can I sort of get it out of here?
Yeah!
I have never seen that.
Get through there.
Hello.
Uh, this is precarious.
Hemis!
It is obligatory that you say Hemis every time you meet a Hemis.
And if you don't say it before you kill them, it's like a lack of respect towards them and their people.
Hemis!
Okay, maybe that's getting a bit too much.
Oh my God, all the Hemis are burning!
Look at him desperately trying to get out of the fire!
He's like dancing.
Everyone's dead now.
I'm not taking that gold.
I'm playing safe.
There's a lot of gold and I chose to leave it.
Something just exploded in the distance.
Something big.
Bait it.
Doink!
Oh wow!
He almost fucked me up.
Unstable teleportation, you love to see it.
Thank you.
So we have 300 money now?
That's the rule, we stick to it, let's go.
And we're not healing, we're saving it.
This is optimal gameplay.
What is that?
Bunch of luminous drill that always casts...
Oh, but it's shuffle, that sucks.
Okay, what do we have for perks?
Oh!
Homing shots, your spells home towards enemies very slightly.
Faster, I don't like that.
Item radar.
You can sense nearby items.
Uh...
Hmm.
I'm not... I want a re-roll, I think.
Protectile repulsion.
The flying to a small sector in front of you get blown away.
Ooh, extra perk.
From now on you will find an extra perk in every holy mountain.
Now that... seems awesome.
I think I want that.
But take it with once everywhere!
Oh, I'm conflicted.
Oh, I don't know.
I don't know.
It's either this one or that one.
I mean, this one is... it's too good, right?
I gotta take it.
No question about it.
I mean, the other one potentially...
or has potential for higher payout in the end.
But as you all know, luck can turn on a dime.
And I'm not taking a chance.
This is the only non... Are you kidding me?
No, this is another non-shuffle wand.
.02... Man, I have no wands at all.
Do I want this?
Yeah.
I don't even have money for it.
Who am I kidding?
I can't afford any of this.
I'm just window shopping.
Let's move.
I have these.
They actually do a decent amount of damage.
And bombs.
It's okay.
Because we can tinker everywhere!
That doesn't matter.
If we find a wand in here...
Bob's your uncle.
And not your nephew.
That's a dead end.
I'm liking the start of this run.
This is great so far.
There's no enemies.
Oh my god, you didn't die?
I thought he died.
Okay.
Shotgun man.
These guys do a lot of that, yeah.
They explode in fireworks.
Very odd enemy.
Because it seems like the fireworks go off in every direction around them.
Like randomly.
Holy shit, the lava though!
That was a bit scary there.
No, I'm leaving the gold.
Even that I'm leaving.
Am I though?
No, I'm not.
Thank you.
Man, we already made it?
I could go through.
Maybe I'm overdoing it with the quickness of things.
Ah, stop standing in that, you idiot.
Swamp is not actually helping too much.
Oh, that's a big guy.
Hitting in there though, I'm gonna leave him.
Stop standing in that.
Oh, everything is fucking green.
You hate to see it.
Oh shit.
This is a nightmare.
Oh my god.
Ah, man.
Don't go that way.
Fuck that guy.
What the hell is this?
Gunpowder in acid?
Or toxic sludge acid, see?
Ah.
Do I want to mess with that?
It would be fun.
No.
I'm so tempted to mess with it.
Oh, look at that.
Yoink.
I appreciate that.
Dead end, huh?
There's also a guy in there.
Let's go right.
Yo.
What the hell is going on here?
Wait a minute.
Why is...
Doesn't this kind of look like an arrow pointing to this?
Wait a minute.
Drain it.
Is there a secret?
Maybe not.
Oh.
Did I hear a shotgun?
No, I heard that one break apart.
Oh, nice.
Another heart.
That's big.
Ouch.
Want to dance?
Come here.
Oh, close one.
Holy crap.
There's lava on the floor.
And there's fire in the heaven.
Or ceiling, I should say.
Oh my god.
Rats.
Nice.
That was pretty smooth.
Oh, we have this guy to deal with.
He's kind of odd.
What is your deal, man?
Such a mysterious enemy.
So far, so good.
300 monies?
Hmm.
Not yet.
I don't have any digging.
Actually, I do have one bomb.
So if I find something...
Oh, what's happening here?
Yo, that guy has a sick wand.
I want it.
He's going to burn to death.
Yes, burn.
Burn, my boy.
Come on.
Oh, please, please burn.
There we go.
Let me get rid of that.
Yo.
That's not bad.
Fuck yeah.
That's a new wand right there.
Main wand achieved.
I like it.
We're back in action.
Well, probably now, I guess.
We were sort of in the action before, but not like back in it.
Only halfway.
This is a good wand.
Ah, dead end.
Weirdly, empty of enemies this level.
I'm going to go here.
Sup, man?
It doesn't bend like that.
Whoops.
Very nice.
I'm so glad I kept going here.
Hello.
What's that?
A fire potion.
How the fuck does that work?
I can drink it.
I think that will damage me.
200% fire.
Look how oddly shaped it is too.
Very interesting.
Very new looking.
Well, I guess I can throw it and explode it on things.
Like a Molotov.
Fire potion.
Wait, this one.
I could go in.
Should I go in?
I'm not sure.
Nah, not yet.
This is such a good run.
And we have a good wand.
We can definitely make some plays happen.
Just a bit more.
Unless we actually explode most.
That can't be true though.
What about to the west?
The fact that I have the capability of clearing so easily, I should take it or use it to my advantage.
Man, I wish I had a teleport wand.
Dead end there.
Just gonna loop back around down here.
Shit, how the fuck do I get back?
Maybe from above.
Yeah, that looks better.
Oh, almost burned myself.
How about all that gold just lying around?
Here we go, here we go.
All that gunpowder.
Wait, this is the one that shoots through walls.
Almost.
I'm not sure, does it?
Yeah, if you stand close to it.
Oh man, the man on this is terrible though.
Wait, what?
Oh, you cannot shoot it if you're too close to a wall.
Oh, okay.
Won't even let you.
Can I get through here?
You know what?
Let's go.
I feel like the game is telling me.
Just go.
Yep.
Do I heal?
Not yet.
Um...
Triple spell, not bad.
I like that.
What is this one again?
Fireball thrower.
That's the one where you turn an intume into one of those, right?
Oh, wait a minute.
Unlimited spells, baby.
I think I need that.
Wait, wait, vampirism.
You lose 25% maximum health.
But can replenish health by drinking blood?
Blood doesn't affect satiation level and you no longer suffer from food poisoning.
Dude.
How is that not amazing?
Like, how much health are we talking?
Drinking blood, dude?
Holy shit.
This is also great.
Immune to fire, oh my god.
I don't know what to pick.
I'm conflicted.
I mean, okay, hold on.
Let's see.
What spells do we have here?
If I want unlimited spells, I better have something good.
Long distance cast.
Take it.
I like this one as well.
All seeing eye.
Take it.
Triple spell.
Yes.
Take it.
Nice.
I think because I don't have any great spells right now that are like good for unlimited.
Maybe I'm not going to take this also because I've tried it before.
Let me try the vampirism.
That sounds crazy to me.
That sounds like infinite healing.
That's what that sounds like to me.
Let's try it, man.
25% of maximum health.
That's totally fine because we don't have a lot of health right now.
Anyway, unless that's like a recurring thing that every time I pick up a new heart, it's less every time.
I don't think it is.
But we'll see.
Then we have energy orb with a timer.
Yeah, I don't know.
I'm not sure about that one.
But watch that one.
That's what I'm talking about.
Yes.
But the mana is bad.
Mana is bad.
Long distance cast.
Wait a minute.
Wait, why is that the...
What?
Why is that so fast?
Why did that...
Okay, so obviously it says cast away minus point.
Oh, wait.
But this one adds point seven five.
Why is it shoot so fast?
Look.
It's like insanity.
Unless...
Wait a minute.
Maybe it doesn't arc like that anymore.
It's always from the same spot.
You know how it goes pop, pop, pop, pop.
That's how the spell works.
Maybe it's always...
It doesn't arc continuously.
Oh no, it actually kind of does.
Bum, bum, bum.
Hmm.
That's weird.
Huh.
That's interesting.
So this one has one twenty one mana thirty nine.
Two fifty forty nine.
Okay.
This is definitely the better one for that.
But what if I do this now?
Instantly, boom.
Yeah.
I think I want to try this, man.
The only issue is...
If someone is close to me, it's kind of rip.
No?
Maybe it's not that good.
Because...
Because of that reason.
I think I just prefer it like this.
Because that's the same.
Wait a minute, let me try something.
Now we do this.
Ha!
What is happening here?
Okay, cast delay is point two five.
Right.
It's being reduced by point oh eight.
And then we add point seventeen.
How the fuck does this make it...
Why is that doing that?
I don't understand what's happening here.
But okay.
Good to know, I guess.
Long distance cast increases or reduces cast delay way more than it says.
Or...
It reduces recharge time?
Because...
Wait a minute.
Look!
No, wait a minute.
If I do like that...
So this is limited by recharge time right now.
Because we have one spell in there, right?
If we add multiple...
Whoops.
Let's see here.
Then it shoots, dump dump, and then it recharge, dump dump, recharge.
But because the recharge and the cast delay is approximately the same here.
And they both sort of add more cast delay.
Bro, there are some of these systems that just don't make sense to me.
The fact that this right here increases the...
Or completely eliminates, I guess?
The recharge time is something that I don't understand.
Let me see in the top right there.
Yeah, why?
I don't understand.
That's so weird.
I'm just gonna rock with that.
But if I only have that...
Let's see here, 107...
Oh, that's a terrible wand!
Holy shit!
That's the worst wand I've ever seen in my life.
100 mana max, 7 mana charge speed, shuffle.
I mean, not that it matters.
It only has one slot, but...
Damn!
That's bad.
Okay.
I definitely want that, I think.
Just have some light, you know?
Can't hurt.
Triple...
Should I go for a triple here instead?
Maybe it's better.
That's caused a lot of mana.
Yeah, it's like OOM instantly.
I don't think that's good.
It is good in theory, but not when you have such a shitty wand with it, so...
I'm actually just gonna rock this, believe it or not.
It sounds boring, but I...
I mean, there's what it is, man!
Unless... electric charge, maybe.
How about we throw that on there?
Plus 3 electric?
Cool.
I mean, it makes it more dangerous, I guess.
If I shoot this while in water...
Oh, and the wand is electric.
Let's not do that.
That's actually kind of bad.
I didn't realize the modifier itself would change the entire wand to be like that.
Okay, dude.
Vampirism?
Let's fucking...
Oh, wait, there's blood here.
Oh, that is... very slow.
But maybe we need a bigger pool of blood, huh?
It's definitely healing!
It's doing!
But it is very... because there's almost no blood here.
But it's actually...
That's sick.
And that's just infinite healing, I guess.
No fucking way.
Where did all this blood come from, anyway?
So I'm saving that heal over there.
We're coming back here.
Later on in the run when we have a million HP.
We can grab that and heal a lot.
Uh-oh.
Ah!
Feels kind of bad that I don't have a better wand for this area.
If we're lucky, we find an electric wand here.
Ah, shit!
You bastard!
It had trouble tracking me.
Oh my god.
Jesus!
Maybe I should have gone for the triple.
Oh my god, this is horrible.
I need a better wand for this place.
I'm totally underpowered.
Let's see if this is the wand.
Mist of spirits?
Maybe.
Let's see.
I don't think making the enemies drunk will help very much.
Am
I healing?
Oh, there's a bunch of blood there.
Hold on, I gotta kill this guy.
Oh my god, it's so difficult, he's so far away.
I should have taken the...
Oh, wait a minute.
I can take her everywhere!
I forgot!
I forgot about that!
Jesus!
Don't wait, I forgot I had that.
This is definitely healing me a lot.
I love it.
I like the vampirism.
I do.
Oh, I don't like that though.
You know what we need now?
We need Wertha, Wertha, Wertha!
That's what we need.
Dude, I can't believe I forgot that I had...
Tinker with Wands everywhere.
That's unreal.
Can you stop blowing?
Thank you.
Also you, stop.
Ah, fuck it.
This is definitely better.
For this area where there's such open areas like this, it's better to have the long range.
It takes a while to kill people though.
Holy shit.
Because we don't have that much damage.
Dear gods, below and above, let me find an electric charger wand.
Like one of those lightning wands.
Whoop!
Damn!
They have the whole artillery.
That's actually kind of sick.
Am I hitting anything?
Maybe.
That guy has a lot of HP.
There we go.
Oh my god!
You surprised me.
Man, there's a severe lack of blood here.
Usually these levels are just overflowing with blood.
Maybe not this level.
But a lot.
Oh my god, I'm almost dead.
Oh shit!
I'm poisoned as fuck.
Oh my god, it's time to get the fuck out.
It's over.
Let's leave.
Oh what?
Oh, I can't get through here at all.
Oh my god, I have nothing that can break ice.
That's surprising.
I think me kicking the ice would break it.
Will this not even break it?
Oh!
Thank god, thank you for opening that door for me.
I don't like this though.
Nice.
There's a sniper somewhere.
Or maybe that was him.
Wait, no.
Nice.
There you are.
I mean, it's not bad.
It does heal, but it's not that much, you know?
But definitely it comes in clutch.
Wait, a bunch of blood just got released from this.
Oh, yes!
Yes.
Okay, so corpses, I just need to fucking rip them apart.
Rip corpses apart and eat them.
Mmm.
Delizioso.
Look at all this healing I did.
Fuck yeah, man.
I'm really starting to warm up to this perk here.
Yo-ho-ho!
Bro!
How am I...
Can I get through that?
That works.
Look at all that blood, baby!
Hold on, I gotta kill that guy.
Oh my god.
Thank you.
Oh, look at the healing, man, it's sick!
I love this perk!
Oh, it's great!
We're full health!
Oh yeah, break that ice.
Break it apart.
Oh, there's no way for me to get up there, is there?
Yikes.
Oh, we're definitely not leaving yet.
No!
All right.
Sniper!
Jam!
I got some knockback on that one.
Holy crap.
Fight!
Please die, will you?
Let me rip that body of yours apart.
Can I?
Does that work when I just eat the corpse?
Like, look, so, okay.
Here's some bodies, right?
What if I kick it?
Release thy blood!
Break it apart.
Hmm, okay, that doesn't heal me at all.
Wow, that suddenly did a lot of stuff to snow.
Break it apart!
Can I kick it?
I guess I'm going up?
Yeah.
Oh, he's frozen as hell.
What's going on there, my dude?
Aha.
Hand it over.
Release the water.
All right.
Man, where are the wands at?
Isn't that interesting?
Holy shit.
Ah, I hate that liquid freezing vapor.
Not liquid.
Freezing vapor.
Look at that, I shoot it through the wall!
You can definitely teleport through walls if you put a teleport on this.
One hundred percent.
Can I really not get...
Oh, there's a lot of blood, that's nice.
Oh, yeah, slurp it up.
Slurp up that blood.
Where does that blood come from?
Man, I cannot get through that.
That is infuriating.
Oh, my God.
I don't have anything.
Yeah, you know what?
Not worth it to go that way.
Anyway, let's move on.
Sometimes it works and I can break the ice, other times it doesn't.
I don't get it.
Drink the blood.
The vampire we are.
Sweet.
I'm actually feeling extremely optimistic about this run, given this vampirism perk.
Like, there's so much potential there.
I need verta, verta, verta, man.
If I find it, I'll take it.
Unless there's a really good one that I would rather have.
Drink up all that blood.
Yeah.
Sixty-nine, baby.
Look at that.
Beautiful.
I won!
Let's see it.
Ooh!
Hold on.
Get out of here!
Let's see.
Critical on oiled enemies.
And a bunch of these.
Actually, not bad.
Replace this one...
Actually, hold on.
Since I can tinker everywhere.
For example, let me drink this blood.
Very good.
Heal that up.
Mmm.
I am gonna take these.
There's actually a bunch of shots here.
Let's take that as well.
That one?
Mmm.
Yeah.
Let's take it.
Let's throw this away, because I don't want it.
Too scary.
Maybe one of these can throw away as well.
I can replace that.
What those?
And then down here...
I can have some more of them.
Because why not?
In fact, just fill this entire one up, please.
And then on the next one...
I don't even know.
Maybe nothing.
Yet.
So here...
I will take...
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Three...
Oh, yeah, doo, doo, doo, doo, doo, doo, doo.
What am I doing?
No, no, no.
I definitely need these on the other one.
This is just a superior wand.
And now we put him on here.
There.
Throw that away, and all of these go away as well.
I don't like that.
Boink!
Nice!
Dude, Tinkit with wands everywhere is so good.
And now I have a sick wand that I can use to shoot people with.
And dig.
Very good.
Let's wait for that freezing vapor, unless we can sort of...
unfreeze it.
Can we actually get rid of that?
I wonder if there's a way.
I can get through here.
Hello.
Oh, my God.
You bastard!
Jesus!
Oh, no.
Not that guy.
That's the worst.
Did I get him?
Oh!
Where is he?
There he is.
I can probably hit him from here.
I got him.
Oh, my goodness.
I hate this vapor!
I hate this vapor so much!
If I fall through it quickly enough...
Oh, okay.
It disappeared.
Why does this look like a boss arena?
Aha!
Ah, it doesn't look too exciting, unfortunately.
Spitterbolts.
I mean, I'll take them.
Hold on.
Why am I suddenly poisoned?
The fuck?
Where did that come from?
Away you go.
Put these up here.
Maybe I'll use them later.
And then we put this back.
I'm tempted to go through.
But I'm also more tempted to drink the blood of my enemies...
before I go through.
Because next up...
is Heezy Base.
And that's some bullshit, ain't it?
And we don't have a lot of HP.
Then again, that is the place to find a lot of blood, isn't it?
You know what?
Let's go.
I believe.
I do believe...
I will not heal.
Because I'm just that much of a badass.
640...
Yo, this has a bunch of stuff.
Oh, man.
If I had taken unlimited spells...
Heh.
This has teleport as well.
Let's see the perks.
Why are there so many lamps?
Revenge explosion.
You release a magical explosion upon taking damage...
and gain 25%.
No.
Invisibility!
That's not bad.
It's been a while since I've seen that one.
Faster projectiles?
I think I'll take this.
Not bad at all.
That's my...
Oh, shit.
I don't have a good enough wand.
Let me just pass right through you.
Wand.
You know?
I'll buy this, I think.
The other ones are not that intriguing.
Gimme.
Give me that one, for sure.
The lands?
Nice.
Water trail?
That's actually really nice!
Get rid of a bunch of toxic shit with that.
Right?
Hell yeah.
Fire... nah, that one goes away.
This one can stay.
That one goes away.
This one can... no, it cannot stay.
Rock?
I'll keep it.
I will keep it, dammit.
Let's get rid of another one of these.
Boing!
Okay.
So that's obviously a teleport wand now.
Water trail?
Let's put that...
10 mana drain.
It's not gonna drain too fast, is it?
Oh, it's actually...
Damn, that's a...
Okay, I was not expecting that amount of water.
Jesus!
I mean, that's dope, though.
I do like that.
Maybe we'll run with that.
Kinda like this as well.
The glowing lands.
Wait a minute.
Was there any one of these wands that had some kind of effect on it?
No, okay.
Hmm.
Pretty cool on oiled enemies.
Maybe I'll make a simple...
You know, I mean, this is... you know what's nice about that one?
30... okay, hold on.
If I put this here...
Is this super fast attack rate as well?
It totally is.
That's the crazy part.
But if it's not there, look.
It's boring old glowing lands.
Except it's not boring, of course, but glowing lands.
Love the glowing lands.
Kinda like it.
Just having a good old glowing lands.
Shooting a trail of water.
I mean...
It's gonna interfere with my blood sucking abilities, though, right?
Isn't it?
Like, am I healing at all right now?
Also, am I okay drinking all that water?
I'm definitely healing, so...
Maybe it prioritizes the...
Also, hold on, what does this say again?
25... you can...
Blood doesn't affect satiation level and you no longer suffer from food poisoning.
Ooh.
Right, that's why I could eat all those corpses, I guess, without puking.
Makes sense to me.
Uhm...
I think I'm good, man.
Chain Bolt, should I?
Hmm...
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
Is it better, I wonder?
You know what?
We're gonna be in close quarters.
So maybe I will...
Hmm.
We're gonna be in close quarters.
So I will actually just go with the glowing lands.
Maybe we put a light on it just for the heck of it, make it look nice.
The water trail is maybe a bit too much.
Maybe we can put it on the...
want there.
Just for the lulz.
We don't really have any digging capabilities right now.
Oh, actually we do, glowing lands?
That does penetrate, doesn't it?
But we don't have extra speed on it, so maybe it doesn't.
It does cut through soft materials.
But last time we had this, we had the speed up on it, and it actually cut through...
uh, metal as well.
Because we teleported through it, remember?
Hell yeah.
Alright, I think we're good to go.
We can always change things later.
So, uh, whoop-dee-wack-a-doo-blah-blah.
We are back in the base.
Miss me, boys!
I'm back!
Hello.
Boink!
Uh...
What the fuck just happened there?
Why was that guy's... Oh, wait, he has a...
He has a wand?
Oh my god.
Hand it over, sir!
What do you got there?
Luminous drill.
You know what?
Hold on.
What if we take this...
and save it?
That's all I wanted to say.
Save that shit!
Is the wand any good?
Actually, yeah.
Dude!
Yeah!
That's actually...
Wait a minute.
That's actually really good.
I just told this shit away.
Uh...
There?
There.
That's a...
Isn't that a great wand?
Like, isn't that a really great...
wand?
Like...
actually amazing wand?
Hello?
Wait a minute.
Let's put that there.
Wait, why is it shooting so slow?
Wait, why...
recharge time is very low, though.
Wait, what?
Why does this take so long to cast?
Recharge time is 0.15.
I don't understand.
Shuffle, no.
Spells will cast one.
It shoots a triple spell.
These all add a bunch...
Okay, wait.
They all add a bunch of...
Oh, I see, I see, I see.
They all add a bunch of castellate to it.
Gotcha.
But look at this one.
That reduces castellate.
So what if I'm cheeky?
Cheeky Nandos.
Okay, that's not very cheeky, is it?
Can I be even more cheeky somehow?
I don't want a long distance cast because...
I'm in close quarters here, right?
Maybe I don't want to use these then.
I have changed my mind.
That's actually just solid.
For now.
This is gonna be a crazy wand later.
For sure.
Hell yeah.
Nice, I like it.
I do like it.
Also...
Oh, but wait a minute.
I can go invisible if I get rid of the water.
That's the big thing.
Doing!
We gotta find some blood.
Holy shit!
Look at all the explosives here.
This is a minefield.
He's stuck in the ceiling.
And there's a bunch of blood here, but there's also fire.
And that scares me a lot.
Yes, it does.
Oh my god, stop burning!
Wait, am I pushing the...
Am I pulling the fire towards me when I...
Okay, that's weird.
So whenever there's any fire in the liquid, if I drink any of the liquid, I take fire damage?
Like, I'm standing here, look.
Drink.
Fire immediately.
I stand here in the center of two fire spots.
Drink.
Fire immediately.
It's like counteracting the healing I'm doing immediately.
What?
That's weird.
Man, I do wish this one had a bit of a less drop off on the shot.
Holy shit.
That is terrible.
Oh, I'm drinking all this blood, baby.
Even the fire's not gonna get me.
Don't care.
I drink that fire.
Easy money.
Look at all that healing.
Oh, yeah.
Sup, boys?
Yikes.
Oh my god, it's a mine.
They don't even die from a shot of this.
Maybe not the best weapon.
Maybe we do change it back.
To be like a... to do a triple one of these bad boys.
That's better, that's better.
It can be a shotgun type deal.
Oh my god, he's not dead yet.
Oh, shit.
Don't blow those up.
I'm warning you.
Damn.
What an explosion.
So I'm not sure I like it, actually.
Honestly, I don't like my spells.
It sucks.
It really sucks.
Stop that.
I want this back.
Trust the old lance.
Right in the tummy.
Good.
Dude, they heal.
What the...
What just happened, dude?
What?
Huh?
The propane tank wasn't even on fire.
What?
Look at it.
It was not on fire.
Huh?
Why did that explode?
I don't understand.
Damn, dude.
What a death.
Well, that sucks.
That was such a good run, though.
I had a crazy amount of good perks.
Well, I had two really good perks, and then I...
Did I have more than two perks?
I'm not sure.
Anyway...
We didn't get anywhere today.
Holy shit.
I mean, we learned some stuff, but other than that...
Not really much else.
Holy damn.
This was a tough one, man.
This game kicked my ass today.
I'm sort of in that same...
situation as I was in Rainworld.
At least today, you know, where...
There's so much resistance from the game.
And I just want the lore, you know?
I just want to find the little secrets.
I want to find out what the fuck is going on.
But I gotta get through this stage of just...
getting to that point where I can do it, you know what I mean?
I mean, I did learn a lot, for sure.
Broke.
Broke 9999.
Damn, you tried all the other combinations and then you finally found one that worked.
Like, ah shit, broke is taken.
Broke 1.
Broke 2.
Probably not.
You haven't learned to fear propane tanks yet.
Maybe I have now.
I've had some experience with propane tanks in the past, okay?
Not just with this game.
I have intimate knowledge of propane tanks and their inner workings.
But that right there didn't make too much sense to me.
It wasn't even on fire.
It was swimming in blood.
I mean, there was a fire next to it, but it didn't touch it.
So what the hell, man?
My theory is that when I drink from the blood, somehow it spreads the fire around.
Because remember, when I drank from the blood when the fire was nowhere near me, I took fire damage.
So maybe when I drink from the blood, all the blood pool is like being fired for like a split second.
And maybe that's what did me in.
It triggered the propane tank.
You know?
Dying to propane tanks never gets old for me.
It's a classic, huh?
Eventually you learn to preventively destroy anything dangerous.
I mean, I did that for the longest time.
But then I stopped doing it because there's just so many explosives.
So that's why you probably need explosion protection.
It's a good perk.
Maybe the tank got warmed up.
Ooh.
That's a good theory.
I didn't think about that, actually.
Even when you try to avoid propane tanks, you die to them for some reason.
I think there's some truth in that.
It's just, get rid of the propane tanks.
Just in general.
I think that's good life advice.
So when you get a job at a warehouse and you see propane tanks there, just yeet them out of there, you know?
And your boss is like, what the fuck are you doing?
You can't have propane tanks here, man.
It's a safety hazard.
Just get rid of them.
Just explode them out in the backyard or out in the back storage area, you know?
They exist solely to end good runs.
I mean, I can see how you may feel that way.
Honestly, myself, I haven't had that many bad experiences with propane tanks.
In fact, I kind of like them a little bit because I can use to throw them into enemies and then explode them.
But I guess they do fuck me up sometimes.
By the way, Oliver, you want to know why the want screen sometimes pops up?
Yes.
Tell me, Lord Eternal, why does that happen?
I'm so curious because I don't know what's going on.
Why does that actually open the screen every time?
Is there a rational explanation for that?
Oliver, I know why your game paused randomly last stream.
Wait, did my game pause randomly?
I don't remember.
It happens when you haven't edited your wants yet.
I think it's supposed to be a reminder to edit your wants.
Oh, that's actually a great explanation.
Didn't even occur to me.
I thought for sure that was a bug.
Ah, okay.
I don't even remember that my game paused randomly.
No, but the mouse cursor is definitely within the game window, even though that setting is not activated.
I can't move it outside.
Or maybe I can, I'm not sure.
I feel like that would totally annoy me if I was able to do that.
But that's actually a pro tip right there.
I'm going to activate that, just in case.
Because if that's the case that it pauses like that, I'm definitely going to activate it.
Like the background buttons at the start of the game.
Okay, yeah.
Makes sense.
Makes sense to me.
Want to know why the spell shot faster with distance cast?
No.
I figured there's an explanation somewhere.
I'll figure it out.
Or not.
That's fine.
All I know is that it works.
So from now on, whenever I use that, I'm just going to think...
I'm going to have faster spells.
There's got to be something that's not explained in the written text there.
You know, some hidden...
something.
Oh, by the way, Cemens!
Thank you for subscribing if you're still here.
I don't know if you're still here.
I see it's 45 minutes ago.
But thank you.
I think the other one's following.
I really appreciate it, people.
I'm just going to say keep testing that.
Oh, I will.
I'm going to test things.
You know the thing about this game?
I think this game is a game I could see myself...
Like, let's say I stop playing it now and start something else.
This is like the game that you just boot up...
a couple times a week.
Because you get that noise of feeling, you know?
And you just want to get back into it.
Even though you may not get anywhere.
It's just like, you get that, oh man, let me just start another run.
Feeling.
It's awesome.
I think that's what this game's going to become for me.
There are ones in this game that once fired, killed the final boss from the spawn location.
I mean, I figured, because someone told me that there was a...
there was a speedrun that did it in less than a second.
So, I don't... yeah.
I mean, I guess that was something to do with that, you know?
But still... kind of insane.
Yeah, that's what I hope Oliver.
That's how it is for me.
I always return to Noisa between other games.
That's how I felt about Starcraft 2 for the longest time.
It's like the game, the constant game in my life that I always go back to...
for like... stints in my life, you know?
Couple months, just hardcore, a lot of Starcraft 2 and then...
maybe I don't play it for a while and then I get back into it, I always come back to it.
Been playing a lot of Battle Aces lately, actually.
It's a new RTS by David Kim, if you know who that is.
Really fun.
Noisa Tingering is like programming language with magic.
Yeah, if programming language didn't have a... didn't have any documentation.
That's what that is.
At least very little.
You know, it's like the most vague documentation.
So, if you want to make like an array of numbers between 1 and 100 with a space of 2 in between, the description for that would be, makes a bunch of numbers, also has a hidden ability.
Like, what the fuck does that mean?
Let me try and use it.
Like, yeah.
A lot of the time you try to logic yourself into thinking or making a wand and then it doesn't make any sense.
Like the chainsaw also has a magic ability, you know?
I don't know what the fuck that is.
Sometimes I just gotta assume there's something going on that is not written and that's fine.
Returns a Boolean.
Unless it doesn't.
I love that one.
Imagine having that in the documentation.
That would be so hilarious.
I guess the wiki and stuff is more akin to documentation.
I guess you're right.
But you know what?
The fact that there's not that much documentation in the game, so to speak, that's what's really promoting the experimentation.
Which is, I think, on purpose and it's awesome.
That's also what made Minecraft so cool for me.
Just experimenting a lot, you know?
I especially liked finding out the potion stuff in Minecraft.
When I finally figured out some, there were some I never figured out, but the ones that I did figure out by experimenting was awesome.
That feeling was unbelievably nice.
Hold
on, why is this so quiet here?
Cartography table!
Oh man.
Yeah, that one.
I mean, I finally understand how it works.
At least I think I did back then at the end.
It's been a while since I've used it at all, so I probably forgot what exactly that did.
I would have to remind myself.
There's a puzzle that is still unsolved in Noita, that's awesome.
That's really cool.
But how do you know there is one?
Did the developers say there is one that didn't get found yet?
That's the only way I can see that.
Unless the game is, like, saying in the menu there are this many secrets and people haven't found them all.
The devs told you, okay.
Interesting.
I wonder if it's a big or small secret.
It doesn't surprise me, this game is oozing with secrets, man.
Oh, you found the secret.
Nobody has been able to solve it yet.
Oh.
Damn.
Huh.
Dude, that sounds like the funniest thing.
To make a game and put in all these secrets and see how the community finds them all, you know, and solves them.
Sounds like a lot of fun to do.
I kind of want to do that one day, if I'm able.
I mean, I don't know how to make games.
But I totally have ideas to tell people how to do it, you know, like, okay, I basically want this secret.
Can you make it?
Just make it, you know?
Would be so much fun designing those things.
Secret can't even be datamined, but that would be boring if people datamined it, though.
It sounds amazing, you jury.
Imagine creating a game like Noitsa.
Sounds so much fun, right?
But, I mean, game development is not always the best thing I hear.
Lots of people are not getting paid very well, and the fucking conditions are horrible.
Doesn't sound like a great time, all in all, but if you're like an indie developer and you have a very successful game, I think that's like the dream.
Right?
Imagine making a game that you made yourself, and it's become so successful, you're living off of it, and you just provide updates to it.
That sounds like so much fun.
That would be the dream, right?
Anyway, guys, I gotta go, man.
It's really late.
This was a long stream.
I was just really feeling the Noitsa today.
I think, even though I got my ass kicked a lot and we didn't get very far, doing all the things that I had on my to-do list here, on my notebook, I think we learned some valuable lessons, you know?
We experimented some, found out a couple things, discovered some new perks, so progress is progress.
So I'm gonna be out of here.
Thank you so much for watching.
It's been a fucking blast, as always.
Love this game.
I'm definitely gonna play it a bit more, I think, for sure.
But maybe within a month, or like less, I'm probably gonna start another game.
And then occasionally return, I think.
So thanks for watching.
I'll see you guys around.
Bye-bye.
Oh, let me raid someone.
Let's do that.
Someone playing Noitsa, let's do that, huh?
Same category?
Let's put it on a guy called Bonfirelo.
He's doing an all-boss speedrun, it seems.
That sounds insane.
I'll just send you over.
Don't feel obligated to stay around for it.
I just think it's a nice thing to do.
Okay, good night.